import 'package:security_plus/flashcard.dart';

List <Flashcard> flash_question_load(){
return([
Flashcard(question: " Typosquatting", answer: "A technique in phishing where the attacker misspells one letter in the URL hoping they won't notice"),
Flashcard(question: " Prepending", answer: "In phishing, adding text at the beginning of the URL"),
Flashcard(question: " Pretexting", answer: "In phishing, lying to get info, such as pretending to be VISA"),
Flashcard(question: " Pharming", answer: "When an attacker wants to target multiple people or servers simultaneously"),
Flashcard(question: " With pharming, attacker takes over entire ___ or ___ so that everyone who visited will be directed to attacker's website", answer: "Website Server"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ redirects everyone to the attacker's server and ___ steals their credentials", answer: "Pharming Phishing"),
Flashcard(question: " In a phishing pharming scenario, it's difficult for even ___ to stop because user thinks it's legit", answer: "Anti-Malware"),
Flashcard(question: " Vishing", answer: "Done over the phone or voicemail, usually fake security checks or bank updates"),
Flashcard(question: " In vishing, caller ID ___ is common to make the phone number look real", answer: "Spoofing"),
Flashcard(question: " Smishing", answer: "Phishing done by SMS, forwards links or asks for info"),
Flashcard(question: " Reconaissance", answer: "Attacker gathers info on the victim"),
Flashcard(question: " The first step for phishers is ___ which is provided on social media and websites", answer: "Gathering Information"),
Flashcard(question: " Step 2 for phishers is to create a ___ since they know where you work and bank", answer: "Believable Pretext"),
Flashcard(question: " Spear Phishing", answer: "Specific targeting phishing using inside information on the victim"),
Flashcard(question: " Whaling", answer: "A spear phishing attack that goes after someone with a lot of control or info, such as a CEO"),
Flashcard(question: " Pretext", answer: "For impersonation; a lie that sets up the context for the attacker's story"),
Flashcard(question: " Impersonation; trap is set ___ the attack", answer: "Before"),
Flashcard(question: " Impersonation", answer: "Attacker pretends to be someone they're not"),
Flashcard(question: " Impersonators attack the victim as someone ___ in rank", answer: "Higher"),
Flashcard(question: " Impersonators use ___ to sound like they know what they're doing", answer: "Technical Terms"),
Flashcard(question: " Eliciting Information", answer: "What the impersonator does to the unknowing victim"),
Flashcard(question: " Impersonation is usually done via ___", answer: "Vishing"),
Flashcard(question: " The goal of the impersonator is to gain ___", answer: "Personal Information"),
Flashcard(question: " A smart thing for a victim to do is to ___ of the impersonator", answer: "Verify the Number"),
Flashcard(question: " Dumpster Diving", answer: "The act of digging through trash receptacles to find information that can be useful in an attack."),
Flashcard(question: " Dumpster diving in the US is ___ unless specified by the people who own it", answer: "Legal"),
Flashcard(question: " Shoulder Surfing", answer: "A form of attack where someone looks at your computer screen to gather info"),
Flashcard(question: " Shoulder surfing is ___", answer: "Surprisingly Easy"),
Flashcard(question: " A good way to prevent shoulder surfing is to use___", answer: "Privacy Filters"),
Flashcard(question: " Computer Hoax", answer: "A threat that doesn't actually exist but seems real, can take many forms"),
Flashcard(question: " Even if the hoax is ineffective, you still have to put in ___", answer: "Time and Resources"),
Flashcard(question: " Some hoaxes try to take money such as by making you buy ___", answer: "Gift Cards"),
Flashcard(question: " A hoax virus can waste as much time as a ___", answer: "Regular Virus"),
Flashcard(question: " A good way to de-hoax is to ___ by using websites like hoaxslayer.com", answer: "Cross Reference"),
Flashcard(question: " Watering Hole Attack", answer: "An attack method that tries to send people to third party websites that are infected"),
Flashcard(question: " Once you visit the watering hole, your ___ become infected too, and the bad guys have a way into your network", answer: "Users"),
Flashcard(question: " Watering hole attacks are directed at ___ groups or organizations", answer: "Particular"),
Flashcard(question: " Layered Defense", answer: "Defense in depth, used to prevent watering hole attacks"),
Flashcard(question: " Spam", answer: "Unsolicited messages sent via email, forums, etc"),
Flashcard(question: " SPIM (spam over internet messaging)", answer: "A spam attack that is propagated through instant messaging rather than email."),
Flashcard(question: " The use of spam is a major ___ issue due to storage costs, security concerns, etc", answer: "Technology"),
Flashcard(question: " Phishing Spam", answer: "A form of spam that asks for your contact information"),
Flashcard(question: " Unsolicited Advertising", answer: "A form of spam that is advertising a product"),
Flashcard(question: " You can use a ___ to stop spam at the gateway before it can reach the user", answer: "Firewall"),
Flashcard(question: " Allowed List", answer: "A method where you only receive emails from trusted senders"),
Flashcard(question: " Spam does not follow ___ standards, so this is a good way to identify it", answer: "SMTP"),
Flashcard(question: " The spam folder can perform a ___ to see if the sender's domain doesn't match the IP address", answer: "Reverse DNS"),
Flashcard(question: " Tarpitting", answer: "the practice of slowing the transmission of e-mail messages sent in bulk as a means of thwarting spammers"),
Flashcard(question: " Recipient Filtering", answer: "Block all email not addressed to a valid recipient email address"),
Flashcard(question: " Influence Campaigns", answer: "Using social engineering to sway attention and sympathy in a particular direction."),
Flashcard(question: " Nation-State Actors", answer: "State-sponsored attackers who try to change the way people are voting or thinking in a particular country"),
Flashcard(question: " Amplification", answer: "A powerful method of influence campaigns using social media to get a message into the eyes and ears of more people"),
Flashcard(question: " Influence campaigns create ___ who post content on many different social media sites", answer: "Fake Users"),
Flashcard(question: " In influence campaigns, the ___ see the content posted by the fake ones, then the media picks up on it", answer: "Real Users"),
Flashcard(question: " Influence campaigns can use ___ to try and influence government officials to change policies", answer: "Military Strategy"),
Flashcard(question: " Cyberwarfare", answer: "The use of computer technology to disrupt the activities of a state or organization"),
Flashcard(question: " Hybrid Warfare", answer: "Combining conventional warfare with cyberwarfare"),
Flashcard(question: " Tailgating", answer: "Use an authorized person to gain unauthorized access to a building"),
Flashcard(question: " Tailgating is often ___", answer: "Intentional"),
Flashcard(question: " Johnny Long/No Tech Hacking", answer: "Wearing third party clothing (Ex. contractor) to have a reason to get access to a facility"),
Flashcard(question: " Tailgating can involve ___ with people so that they will let you in when it's time to go back to work", answer: "Smoking"),
Flashcard(question: " Tailgating is important to prevent because the security door is the ___ barrier guarding sensitive info", answer: "Last"),
Flashcard(question: " Access Control Vestibule", answer: "A method that prevents tailgating by allowing only one person through at a time"),
Flashcard(question: " Invoice Scam", answer: "Attacker sends a fake bill to an organization that looks like it needs to be paid"),
Flashcard(question: " Accounting will pay for invoice scam because it can look like it came from the ___", answer: "CEO"),
Flashcard(question: " Credential Harvesting", answer: "The attacker tries to access all of your stored usernames and passwords"),
Flashcard(question: " In credential harvesting, the attacker will send you a word document, and clicking it runs a ___ which then downloads your credentials to the attacker", answer: "Macro"),
Flashcard(question: " In credential harvesting, everything is running in the ___, making users often unaware", answer: "Background"),
Flashcard(question: " Social engineering is ___", answer: "Constantly Changing"),
Flashcard(question: " Social engineering often uses ___ people or organizations in the attack", answer: "Multiple"),
Flashcard(question: " A lot of social engineering these days uses ___", answer: "Open Source Intelligence"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers can send ___ of someone you know as a way to appeal to emotion", answer: "Funeral Notifications"),
Flashcard(question: " Authority", answer: "Technique where the social engineer claims to be someone of power, like a CEO or cop"),
Flashcard(question: " Intimidation", answer: "A social engineering effectiveness principle in which the victim is frightened and coerced by threat"),
Flashcard(question: " Scarcity/Urgency", answer: "Social engineering technique where attackers make it seem like it needs to happen quickly"),
Flashcard(question: " Familiarity/Liking", answer: "Someone you know we have common friends (social engineering)"),
Flashcard(question: " Trust", answer: "Social engineering technique pretending to be someone safe, such as IT guy here to help"),
Flashcard(question: " Naoki Hiroshima", answer: "Case where attacker got last 4 of credit card number from PayPal, then called GoDaddy with this info and kept guessing the first 2 until getting it right"),
Flashcard(question: " Malware", answer: "Malicious software that is going to do something that impacts you negatively"),
Flashcard(question: " Malware tries to ___ which is then sent back to the attacker", answer: "Gather Information"),
Flashcard(question: " Botnet", answer: "A logical computer network of zombies under the control of a third party, the attacker."),
Flashcard(question: " Several forms of malware ___", answer: "Work Together"),
Flashcard(question: " To prevent getting malware from emails, ___", answer: "Don't Click Links"),
Flashcard(question: " Virus", answer: "Malware that can reproduce itself"),
Flashcard(question: " The virus needs you to ___ in order to activate", answer: "Execute the Program"),
Flashcard(question: " Some viruses are ___ and some can cause serious problems", answer: "Invisible"),
Flashcard(question: " Anti-Virus", answer: "Very common, can stop thousands of new viruses every week"),
Flashcard(question: " Update your ___ to keep viruses from executing", answer: "Signature File"),
Flashcard(question: " Program Virus", answer: "Part of an application that when launched, runs virus"),
Flashcard(question: " Boot Sector Virus", answer: "Replicates itself onto a hard drive's master boot record, then launches when computer boots up"),
Flashcard(question: " Script Virus", answer: "Operating system and browser-based"),
Flashcard(question: " Macro Virus", answer: "Virus that runs inside an application, common in Microsoft Office"),
Flashcard(question: " Fileless Virus", answer: " A stealth attack good at avoiding antivirus but never installed in a file or application"),
Flashcard(question: " Filess Virus operates in the ___ of the computer", answer: "Memory"),
Flashcard(question: " Usually you get a fileless virus by clicking a link in a ___ or ___ which then downloads the software", answer: "Website Email"),
Flashcard(question: " Worm", answer: "Malware that self-replicates like wildfire and does not need the user to do anything"),
Flashcard(question: " Worms can take over thousands and sometimes millions of systems ___", answer: "Very Quickly"),
Flashcard(question: " Once the worm is identified, you can stop it at the ___ or the ___", answer: "Firewall IPS"),
Flashcard(question: " Wannacry Worm", answer: "May 12, 2017 this worm propagated fast and encrypted personal files"),
Flashcard(question: " Personal Data", answer: "The most valuable thing we own"),
Flashcard(question: " Organization Data", answer: "Even more valuable, data owned by a company"),
Flashcard(question: " Ransomware", answer: "Attacker takes your data and locks computer and makes you pay to get it back"),
Flashcard(question: " Ransomware ___ be avoided if security professional removes malware", answer: "Can"),
Flashcard(question: " Crypto Malware", answer: "A new form of ransomware that locks away your data until you pay for the decryption key; better than a hoax"),
Flashcard(question: " Always have an ___ to protect against ransomware", answer: "Offline Backup"),
Flashcard(question: " Another way to prevent ransomware is to make sure everything is ___", answer: "Updated"),
Flashcard(question: " Trojan", answer: "Software that pretends to be something else to conquer computer"),
Flashcard(question: " Trojans can appear harmless to you as well as your ___", answer: "Antivirus Software"),
Flashcard(question: " PUP Potentially Unwanted Program", answer: "Identified by anti virus and often installed with other software"),
Flashcard(question: " Trojans and malware open a ___ so they can easily reconnect to the system", answer: "Backdoor"),
Flashcard(question: " Some malware software can take advantage of backdoors created by ___", answer: "Other Malware"),
Flashcard(question: " Some lower and older versions of software had a ___", answer: "Backdoor"),
Flashcard(question: " RAT Remote Access Trojan", answer: "Gives a third party access to your computer to have nearly complete control over operating system"),
Flashcard(question: " The ___ in rootkit was originally a ___ technique", answer: "Root Unix"),
Flashcard(question: " Rootkits modify files in the ___ of the operating system", answer: "Kernel"),
Flashcard(question: " Rootkits are ___ to operating and antivirus systems once they dig in", answer: "Invisible"),
Flashcard(question: " Zeus/Zbot Malware", answer: "Botnet malware used to clean out bank accounts,"),
Flashcard(question: " The rootkit that made sure you couldn't uninstall Zbot", answer: "Necurs"),
Flashcard(question: " The core of an operating system that has complete control over everything in it", answer: "Kernel"),
Flashcard(question: " Can see if any part of the kernel has changed to prevent the installation of rootkits", answer: "UEFI BIOS"),
Flashcard(question: " Rootkit removers are usually built ___ the rootkit is installed", answer: "After"),
Flashcard(question: " A software program that delivers advertising content everywhere, which weakens computer performance", answer: "Adware"),
Flashcard(question: " The application designed to remove adware could itself be ___", answer: "Malware"),
Flashcard(question: " Malware that collects information from a computer without the user's knowledge, such as key presses or PII", answer: "Spyware"),
Flashcard(question: " Spyware is often a ___", answer: "Keylogger"),
Flashcard(question: " Spyware that records every keystroke made on a computer to steal personal information or passwords or to launch Internet attacks.", answer: "Keylogger"),
Flashcard(question: " The main reason so many people use adware and spyware", answer: "money"),
Flashcard(question: " Tool used to clean computer of adware and spyware", answer: "Malwarebytes"),
Flashcard(question: " Once your computer is infected it becomes this", answer: "Bot"),
Flashcard(question: " Bots get on your computer via a ___ and can control almost any aspect of operating system", answer: "Trojan Horse"),
Flashcard(question: " A botnet is controlled through a ___ server", answer: "Command and Control"),
Flashcard(question: " Responsible for sending out commands to botnet", answer: "C and C Server"),
Flashcard(question: " Massive attack committed using dozens of computers, usually zombies on a botnet.", answer: "DDoS"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ can be rented out from third parties", answer: "Botnets"),
Flashcard(question: " Website that shows a map of active botnets and live attacks", answer: "LookingGlass.Com"),
Flashcard(question: " As with most malware, the best way to prevent bots is to keep your OS and antivirus software ___", answer: "Updated"),
Flashcard(question: " You can identify an active malware infection by running an ___ malware scan", answer: "On-Demand"),
Flashcard(question: " A computer program or part of a program that lies dormant until it is triggered by a specific event", answer: "Logic Bomb"),
Flashcard(question: " Logic bombs are commonly left by people with ___", answer: "Grudges"),
Flashcard(question: " Type of logic bomb that activates on a particular date", answer: "Time Bomb"),
Flashcard(question: " Logic bombs are difficult to find because they do not follow any known ___", answer: "Signature"),
Flashcard(question: " Many logic bombs will ___ once executed", answer: "Delete Themselves"),
Flashcard(question: " Logic bomb in Korea in March 19 and 20 2013 began deleting ___ upon activation", answer: "Master Boot Records"),
Flashcard(question: " Logic bomb in Ukraine 2016 began disabling ___", answer: "Electrical Circuits"),
Flashcard(question: " Manages electrical systems, was attacked by logic bomb in Ukraine", answer: "SCADA"),
Flashcard(question: " Can use this to scan for changes in your computer activity and prevent logic bombs from going off", answer: "HIPS"),
Flashcard(question: " Stored passwords with no encryption; rare but attackers love them", answer: "Plain Text"),
Flashcard(question: " Represent data as a fixed-length string of text (a message digest or fingerprint)", answer: "Hashes"),
Flashcard(question: " You can provide an ___ to the hash which will not be duplicated on the system", answer: "Input"),
Flashcard(question: " Cryptographic algorithm that can't be reversed (hash)", answer: "One Way Trip"),
Flashcard(question: " An implementation of SHA-2 using a 256-bit hash, very common", answer: "SHA-256"),
Flashcard(question: " The hash is ___ from the original password", answer: "Very Different"),
Flashcard(question: " There is no way to ___ hash back to original password", answer: "Reverse"),
Flashcard(question: " Shows usernames accompanied by the hash that was created by the password", answer: "Password File"),
Flashcard(question: " Tries to log onto a system with a few common passwords before moving on.", answer: "Spraying Attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Try every possible password combination until the hash is matched", answer: "Brute Force"),
Flashcard(question: " A ___ can slow a brute force attack down", answer: "Strong Hashing Algorithm"),
Flashcard(question: " Brute force is less effective ___ because it's slow and you can get locked out", answer: "Online"),
Flashcard(question: " It's more common to download the password file so that attackers can brute force the ___", answer: "Hash Offline"),
Flashcard(question: " Attacker encrypts every word in a dictionary using same cryptosystem used by target.", answer: "Dictionary Attacks"),
Flashcard(question: " Dictionary attacks can involve finding ___ on the internet", answer: "Wordlists"),
Flashcard(question: " Password crackers in dictionary attacks can ___", answer: "Substitute Letters"),
Flashcard(question: " Since dictionary attacks take time, attackers commonly use ___ cracking or ___ cracking", answer: "Distributed GPU"),
Flashcard(question: " Database of precomputed hashes from sequentially calculated passwords", answer: "Rainbow Table"),
Flashcard(question: " Rainbow Tables have remarkable ___ because there is no calculation process of creating the hash", answer: "Speed Increase"),
Flashcard(question: " Applications have ___ ways of creating hashes, so you need the right rainbow table", answer: "Different"),
Flashcard(question: " A little bit of extra data added to the password before it is hashed", answer: "Salt"),
Flashcard(question: " People will have different hashes even if they have the ___ because of the salt", answer: "Same Password"),
Flashcard(question: " Every user gets their own ___", answer: "Random Salt"),
Flashcard(question: " Rainbow tables do not work with ___", answer: "Salted Hashes"),
Flashcard(question: " Adding salt will ___ the brute force process", answer: "Slow Down"),
Flashcard(question: " Looks normal but has extra parts inside, downloads malicious software once plugged in", answer: "Malicious USB Cable"),
Flashcard(question: " Newer operating systems no longer automatically run files as a security precaution against a ___", answer: "Malicious Flash Drive"),
Flashcard(question: " Start a command prompt any type anything you want without intervention", answer: "HID Human Interface Device"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers can still load malware in ___", answer: "Documents"),
Flashcard(question: " A malicious flash drive can still act as a ___", answer: "Boot Device"),
Flashcard(question: " Stealing information from a credit card by swiping it through a processing machine that gathers the information", answer: "Skimming"),
Flashcard(question: " Includes a small camera to watch for your PIN", answer: "ATM Skimming"),
Flashcard(question: " The practice of making an unauthorized copy of a credit card.", answer: "Card Cloning"),
Flashcard(question: " Card cloning only works on cards with the ___ , not the chip", answer: "Magnetic Stripe"),
Flashcard(question: " Cloning ___ is very common due to magnetic stripes", answer: "Gift Cards"),
Flashcard(question: " A type of artificial intelligence that leverages massive amounts of data so that computers can improve the accuracy of actions and predictions on their own without additional programming.", answer: "Machine Learning"),
Flashcard(question: " Machine learning requires a lot of ___", answer: "Training Data"),
Flashcard(question: " Machine learning is in use___ to identify spam or recommend products or movies", answer: "Every Day"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers can send ___ to cause the AI to behave incorrectly", answer: "Modified Training Data"),
Flashcard(question: " Microsoft did not program this bot to be non-offensive, so Twitter users turned her into a racist", answer: "Tay"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers find ___ and ___ with AI training", answer: "Holes Limitations"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers can ___ the formatting of spam messages to fool the AI into doing something its not supposed to", answer: "Slightly Change"),
Flashcard(question: " A good preventative measure for machine learning is to ___ constantly with new and better data", answer: "Retrain"),
Flashcard(question: " You can also train the AI with possible ___ so it can identify what is bad", answer: "Poisoning"),
Flashcard(question: " Chain of manufacturing that gets a product from very beginning to very end of its process", answer: "Supply Chain"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers can infect ___ step along the way because it is easy for us to trust our ___", answer: "Any Suppliers"),
Flashcard(question: " 40 million credit cards were stolen from this company in a supply chain attack stealing HVAC credentials", answer: "Target"),
Flashcard(question: " Two groups say that there are two categories for IT security which are ___ data and ___ data", answer: "On-Premises Cloud-Based"),
Flashcard(question: " Centralized and costs less; no data center to secure; third party handles everything", answer: "Cloud-Based Security"),
Flashcard(question: " Puts security burden on client, data center and infrastructure security costs", answer: "On-Premises Security"),
Flashcard(question: " If your data is on premises, you have ___ of security and IT teams", answer: "Complete Control"),
Flashcard(question: " A local team can be ___ and ___", answer: "Expensive Difficult"),
Flashcard(question: " Local team maintains ___ and ___", answer: "Uptime Availability"),
Flashcard(question: " Security changes can ___", answer: "Take Time"),
Flashcard(question: " In cloud-based, the data is in a secure environment and there is no ___ to it", answer: "Physical Access"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ may have access to cloud based data", answer: "Third Party"),
Flashcard(question: " Cloud providers are managing ___ security", answer: "Large Scale"),
Flashcard(question: " Cloud based users must follow security ___", answer: "Best-Practices"),
Flashcard(question: " While cloud based may have scalable security options, they may not be as ___ as necessary", answer: "Customizable"),
Flashcard(question: " In a cryptographic attack, the attacker does not have the key so they break the ___ (cryptography)", answer: "Safe"),
Flashcard(question: " Attacker spend a lot of time trying to find ___", answer: "Cryptographic Vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " In birthday attack, chance of 2 out of 23 students having the same birthday is ___", answer: "0.5"),
Flashcard(question: " Occurs when the hashing algorithm creates the same hash from different plaintext", answer: "Hash Collision"),
Flashcard(question: " You can find a hash collision through ___", answer: "Brute Force"),
Flashcard(question: " In a birthday attack, the attacker will generate ___ of plaintext to match the hashes", answer: "Multiple Versions"),
Flashcard(question: " Protect yourself from birthday attacks with large ___", answer: "Hash Output Size"),
Flashcard(question: " Are not supposed to happen since different input data shouldn't create the same hash", answer: "Hash Collisions"),
Flashcard(question: " Message Digest Algorithm 5 first published in___ and had collisions identified in ___", answer: "1992 1996"),
Flashcard(question: " In 2008, it was discovered the MD5", answer: "Fake CA"),
Flashcard(question: " Sit in the middle of two devices and force them to communicate at a lower level encryption", answer: "Downgrade Attack"),
Flashcard(question: " The encryption we use to communicate to web servers", answer: "TLS"),
Flashcard(question: " Because of ___ we will never fall back to ___", answer: "POODLE SSL 3.0"),
Flashcard(question: " An attack that exploits a vulnerability in software to gain access to resources that the user normally would be restricted from accessing.", answer: "Privilege Escalation"),
Flashcard(question: " With privilege escalation, any user can be an ___", answer: "Administrator"),
Flashcard(question: " Privilege escalation attacks are ___ vulnerability patches and need to get handled right away", answer: "High-Priority"),
Flashcard(question: " A safeguard for privilege escalation that only allows apps to run in areas of memory where it is allowed", answer: "Data Execution Prevention"),
Flashcard(question: " Randomizing stored memory so if attacker exploits memory address on one system he can't duplicate it on another OS", answer: "Address Space Layout Randomization (ASLR)"),
Flashcard(question: " Privilege escalation that affects many different Windows operating systems, has many variations", answer: "CVE 2020-1530"),
Flashcard(question: " Browser vulnerability that allows info from one site to be shared with another", answer: "XSS (Cross Site Scripting)"),
Flashcard(question: " XSS is commonly found on ___ applications", answer: "Web-Based"),
Flashcard(question: " XSS attackers can use ___ in conjunction with a vulnerable website", answer: "Javascript"),
Flashcard(question: " XSS attack where website allows scripts to run in user input (search box common source)", answer: "Non Persistent (Reflected)"),
Flashcard(question: " In non persistent XSS the attacker sends a specific link predominantly through ___", answer: "Email"),
Flashcard(question: " User in non persistent XSS clicks link to run ___ embedded in URL", answer: "Malicious Scripts"),
Flashcard(question: " An easy way to find if a field is vulnerable to XSS is to use the ___ or ___ methods", answer: "alert() concole.log()"),
Flashcard(question: " A ___ XSS attack can be stored permanently on a server and anyone visiting the page would be running the script", answer: "Persistent (Stored)"),
Flashcard(question: " Persistent XSS attacks are often on websites with ___ or ___", answer: "Messages Forum Posts"),
Flashcard(question: " Persistent XSS attacks are ___ in social media posts, and everyone who reads it gets the malicious script", answer: "Embedded"),
Flashcard(question: " Discovered XSS on Subaru site where token never expired and he could log back in without credentials", answer: "Aaron Guzman June 2017"),
Flashcard(question: " In Subaru attack, attacker could ___ to someone's token and gain full access to their car", answer: "Add Their Email"),
Flashcard(question: " Attacker inputs their own code into an existing data stream", answer: "Code Injection"),
Flashcard(question: " Code injection is often enabled because of ___ within an application", answer: "Bad Programming"),
Flashcard(question: " Applications should not allow you to put your ___ into a data stream", answer: "Own Code"),
Flashcard(question: " The most common relational database management system language", answer: "SQL (Structured Query Language)"),
Flashcard(question: " An attack that targets SQL servers by injecting commands to be manipulated by the database.", answer: "SQL Injection"),
Flashcard(question: " If a web front end does not validate anything typed into authentication number, you can modify it by ___ at the end of the number", answer: "Adding SQL"),
Flashcard(question: " Often used to transfer data between two different kinds of devices", answer: "XML (Extensible Markup Language)"),
Flashcard(question: " Involves sending malformed XML to a separate device", answer: "XML Injection"),
Flashcard(question: " Often used to store information about authentication, such as username and password", answer: "LDAP (Lightweight Directory Access Protocol)"),
Flashcard(question: " An application attack that targets web-based applications by fabricating LDAP statements that are typically created by user input.", answer: "LDAP Injection"),
Flashcard(question: " Windows library containing code and data, used by many applications", answer: "DLL (Dynamic Link Library)"),
Flashcard(question: " Insert a code into an application to have that application execute the code for us (B->A, Runs B code as A)", answer: "DLL Injection"),
Flashcard(question: " Occurs when one section of memory is able to overwrite a different section of memory by", answer: "Buffer Overflow Attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Many programming languages perform this, which means they do not allow a program to use an invalid array subscript.", answer: "Bounds Checking"),
Flashcard(question: " Buffer overflows are not a ___ for attackers", answer: "Simple Exploit"),
Flashcard(question: " A good buffer overflow for an attacker is one they can both ___ and ___", answer: "Replicate Control"),
Flashcard(question: " Occurs when the attacker captures a portion of a communication between two parties and retransmits it at a later time", answer: "Replay Attack"),
Flashcard(question: " In a replay attack, the attacker will gather information and then ___ to make it seem like it was coming from you", answer: "Replay Data"),
Flashcard(question: " Being ___ between the two devices is not a requirement for the actual replay attack", answer: "On the Path"),
Flashcard(question: " Attacker intercepts hash and replays it to server posing as original user that sent it", answer: "Pass the Hash"),
Flashcard(question: " A good way to prevent pass the hash is to use a ___ or an ___", answer: "Salt Encryption"),
Flashcard(question: " Salting a hash is useful because even if an attacker gets the hash, he can't reuse it because it is a ___ password", answer: "One Time"),
Flashcard(question: " Information stored on your computer by the browser", answer: "Cookies"),
Flashcard(question: " Cookies can contain ___ which attackers can use to pose as you when communicating with someone else", answer: "Session IDs"),
Flashcard(question: " Stealing a user's session ID to pose as the user and not have to log in with a username or password", answer: "Session Hijacking (Sidejacking)"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers gather session information using ___ or ___to gather it from wired or wireless networks", answer: "Wireshark Kislet"),
Flashcard(question: " Once the attacker has the session ID info, they need to ___ that are being sent to the server", answer: "Modify The Headers"),
Flashcard(question: " One way to prevent replay and session attacks is to make sure all communication between both sides is ___", answer: "Always Encrypted"),
Flashcard(question: " The ___ in your browser determines where it is going to go to gather the info required to make up that page", answer: "HTML"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ such as clicking a YouTube link on someone else's website is a way to gather info without the victim knowing", answer: "Browser Trust"),
Flashcard(question: " Website pages consist of ___ code and ___ code", answer: "Client-Side Server-Side"),
Flashcard(question: " Info rendering in browser to show clients and text", answer: "Client Side"),
Flashcard(question: " Used to perform back end processes such as your bank transferring data or uploading video", answer: "Server Side"),
Flashcard(question: " Exploits the trust a site has in the user's browser. Tricks a user into sending unauthorized commands to a web application", answer: "Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF or XSRF)"),
Flashcard(question: " Web applications should have anti-forgery techniques such as a ___", answer: "Cryptographic Token"),
Flashcard(question: " An XSRF attacker can make a funds transfer request by emailing a ___ and hoping the victim is already logged in", answer: "Hyperlink"),
Flashcard(question: " Where attacker finds vulnerable web application, then web server performs requests on behalf of attacker", answer: "Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF)"),
Flashcard(question: " To prevent SSRF the server should always validate the ___ to the server and the ___", answer: "Input Output"),
Flashcard(question: " In SSRF the attacker will send a request to the server that will require it to perform ___ in the background", answer: "Another Function"),
Flashcard(question: " In the Capital One attack the ___ was misconfigured allowing it to be queried and gather information", answer: "WAF (Web Application Firewall)"),
Flashcard(question: " Traditional anti-virus software is very good at stopping ___ vulnerabilities", answer: "Known"),
Flashcard(question: " Drivers are a perfect conduit for a malware attack because they are ___ by your operating system", answer: "Trusted"),
Flashcard(question: " Used on operating system, such as Windows compatibility mode (backwards compatibility)", answer: "Shimming"),
Flashcard(question: " Malware authors can write their ___ to get around security such as Windows User Account Control", answer: "Own Shims"),
Flashcard(question: " When your system downloads malware it is downloading a unique version that won't match signatures in your antivirus software", answer: "Refactoring (Metamorphic Malware)"),
Flashcard(question: " In refactoring the attacker makes the malware ___ every time", answer: "Appear Different"),
Flashcard(question: " To detect refactoring you need to use a ___ rather than signature-based detection", answer: "Layered Approach"),
Flashcard(question: " Combines an on-path attack with a downgrade attack;", answer: "Difficult to implement, but big returns for the attacker"),
Flashcard(question: " For SSL stripping, attacker sits in the ___ of the conversation between client and server", answer: "Middle"),
Flashcard(question: " Proxying", answer: "Sitting in the middle of attack to modify communication between web site visitor and web server"),
Flashcard(question: " In SSL stripping attacker ___ request for HTTPS by web server and sends it back to web server", answer: "Intercerpts"),
Flashcard(question: " In SSL stripping after attacker sends back HTTPS request it will set up an ___ between only the attacker and web server", answer: "Encrypted Channel"),
Flashcard(question: " In SSL stripping after attacker has established the encrypted channel he will send the ___ back to website visitor", answer: "Non-Encrypted Page"),
Flashcard(question: " In SSL stripping website visitor has ___ that any changes were made in the middle", answer: "No Idea"),
Flashcard(question: " In SSL stripping if website visitor sends the ___ and ___ the attacker can see it and log in with the credentials", answer: "Username Password"),
Flashcard(question: " Race Condition", answer: "Multiple threads trying to interact with the same system at the same time. i.e. husband and wife both trying to withdraw from same account at same time."),
Flashcard(question: " TOCTOU attack", answer: "Checking for things to occur on a system and making changes knowing there might be other changes happening"),
Flashcard(question: " Memory Leak", answer: "Memory never returns to system, so system uses more and more until it uses all of it and crashes system"),
Flashcard(question: " Null Pointer Dereference", answer: "Attacker points to a section of memory where nothing exists, which often causes system to crash"),
Flashcard(question: " Integer Overflow", answer: "Large number is placed into smaller section of memory, forcing extra space to go where memory is overflowed"),
Flashcard(question: " Directory Traversal", answer: "Attackers can read from different parts of a web server, even ones they do not have access to"),
Flashcard(question: " Error messages should show ___ information so that nothing sensitive is shared and they can be reported", answer: "Just Enough"),
Flashcard(question: " All input should be considered ___", answer: "Malicious"),
Flashcard(question: " API (Application Programming Interface)", answer: "Attackers try to manipulate the interface so they can gain additional access or even bring down the system"),
Flashcard(question: " API", answer: "Sends multiple programming interface requests to the server rather than just one"),
Flashcard(question: " DoS", answer: "Can often be done on a single device with no bandwidths"),
Flashcard(question: " DoS", answer: "Attack that uses up available resources on a device so that the application is no longer accessible to others"),
Flashcard(question: " Zip Bomb", answer: "A very small zip file 42kb that when unzipped it expands to 4500 terabytes"),
Flashcard(question: " DHCP Starvation", answer: "Attacker floods network with IP address requests to make it seem like there are many machines on network"),
Flashcard(question: " DCHP starvation makes network ___ to anyone else because all IP addresses have been used", answer: "Unavailable"),
Flashcard(question: " Rogue Access Point", answer: "Access point added to your network without your authorization"),
Flashcard(question: " It is important to use ___ so that are forced to provide authentication before being allowed access to the network", answer: "Network Access Control"),
Flashcard(question: " Wireless Evil Twin", answer: "Designed to look exactly like access points on your network (eg same SSID) but is actually malicious"),
Flashcard(question: " An evil twin, if close enough, can ___ the signal from the other access points and become the main access point", answer: "Overpower"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ are easy to fool with evil twins", answer: "WiFi Hotspots"),
Flashcard(question: " Bluejacking", answer: "An attack that sends unsolicited messages to Bluetooth-enabled devices"),
Flashcard(question: " Since typical Bluetooth range is ___ the attacker would have to be close to send a Bluejacking message", answer: "10 meters"),
Flashcard(question: " Bluesnarfing", answer: "When an attacker can access data on your mobile device using the Bluetooth communications channel"),
Flashcard(question: " Wireless Disassociation Attack", answer: "A DoS attack that is specifically causing devices on the wireless network to not communicate to access point"),
Flashcard(question: " Management Frames", answer: "Your mobile device sends a number of these to the access point, which in turn replies with the same ones"),
Flashcard(question: " Management Frames", answer: "Manage quality of service and association/disassociation with access point"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ did not add protection for management frames, making them vulnerable to attackers", answer: "Original Wireless Standards"),
Flashcard(question: " Sending ___ will disconnect the device from the network", answer: "Deauthentication Frames"),
Flashcard(question: " 802.11w", answer: "Update made in 2014 to protect against deauthorization attacks"),
Flashcard(question: " Certain management frames such as authentication or association need to be ___ in order to connect to device", answer: "Unencrypted"),
Flashcard(question: " 802.11w is required for ___ compliance", answer: "802.11ac"),
Flashcard(question: " Radio Frequency Jamming", answer: "Decrease the signal-to-noise ratio so receiving device can't hear the good signal"),
Flashcard(question: " Signal-to-Noise Ratio", answer: "Makes sure that the signal is louder than the background noise"),
Flashcard(question: " To be able to disrupt devices on local wireless network, the jamming needs to be ___", answer: "Close"),
Flashcard(question: " Fox Hunt", answer: "Directional antenna and headphones, move around to find jamming signal"),
Flashcard(question: " RFID (Radio Frequency Identification)", answer: "Uses radio signals to communicate with a tag placed in or attached to an object, almost anywhere"),
Flashcard(question: " RFID Attacks", answer: "Attacks against radio frequencies including eavesdropping, replay, and DoS"),
Flashcard(question: " NFC (Near Field Communication)", answer: "A form of radio communication that transfers data wirelessly over very short distances (usually 10 cm or less)."),
Flashcard(question: " Cryptography", answer: "Randomizes data so it looks nothing like plain text"),
Flashcard(question: " Without___ an encrypted string of data looks very similar to the original, allowing attackers to reverse engineer it (Puppy example)", answer: "Randomization"),
Flashcard(question: " Electronic Code Book (ECB)", answer: "A process in which plaintext is divided into blocks and each block is then encrypted separately."),
Flashcard(question: " Nonce", answer: "An arbitrary number that can only be used once"),
Flashcard(question: " We often use a cryptographic nonce during the ___ process, then combine it with the hash", answer: "Login"),
Flashcard(question: " Initialization Vector (IV)", answer: "A type of nonce that adds randomization to the encryption method making it stronger"),
Flashcard(question: " Salt", answer: "Makes sure the passwords we are storing are randomized across all users on the system"),
Flashcard(question: " On-Path", answer: "Network attack where someone in the middle can intercept and sometimes change data between two stations"),
Flashcard(question: " In on-path the attacker can ___ or ___ the info before sending it to the intended recipient", answer: "Read Modify"),
Flashcard(question: " ARP Poisoning", answer: "On path attack on local IP subnet, has no security, making it easy for attackers to modify and send"),
Flashcard(question: " Address Resolution Protocol (ARP)", answer: "Message sent to router in the form of router's IP address so that router can send back the MAC address"),
Flashcard(question: " ARP Cache", answer: "Storage for received MAC addresses on computer so it does not have to use ARP every time"),
Flashcard(question: " For an ARP attack to work, the attacker needs to be on the ___", answer: "Local Network"),
Flashcard(question: " In ARP poisoning the attacker sends an ___ ARP message to the device it wants to poison", answer: "Unrequested"),
Flashcard(question: " Once the target has been poisoned, any information will be sent the the MAC address of the ___", answer: "Attacker"),
Flashcard(question: " After poisoning the victim, the attacker then poisons the ___", answer: "Router"),
Flashcard(question: " On-Path Browser Attack", answer: "Malware that is the relay between victim and devices exists on the same computer as the victim"),
Flashcard(question: " For on-path browser attack, an ___ within the malware on the victim's computer is handling the relay", answer: "Automated Process"),
Flashcard(question: " For on-path browser attack, attacker can see victim's data in ___ form before it is sent", answer: "Unencrypted"),
Flashcard(question: " For on path browser attack, malware waits for you to ___ to something such as the bank, then cleans you out", answer: "Login"),
Flashcard(question: " MAC Address", answer: "Physical address of a network adapter, unique to a device"),
Flashcard(question: " In ethernet, MAC address is ___ long and displayed in ___", answer: "48 bits Hexadecimal"),
Flashcard(question: " Organizationally Unique Identifier (OUI)", answer: "The first 3 bytes of the MAC address that identifies the manufacturer of the network hardware"),
Flashcard(question: " Serial Number", answer: "The last three bytes of the MAC address, used for every network interface card a company manufactures"),
Flashcard(question: " Switch", answer: "Maintains a list of all the MAC addresses that it knows about on local network so it knows when to receive a particular frame"),
Flashcard(question: " STP (Spanning Tree Protocol)", answer: "Prevent loops in switch"),
Flashcard(question: " If a switch receives an ___ MAC address it will add it and the output interface to the table inside the switch", answer: "Unknown"),
Flashcard(question: " MAC Flooding", answer: "Since switches have limited MAC addresses, attackers can send different ones to the switch to force out the legitimate ones"),
Flashcard(question: " Once MAC flooding is complete, the switch becomes a ___ and transmits all traffic, becoming vulnerable to attackers", answer: "Hub"),
Flashcard(question: " Many switch port ___ can take preventative measures against MAC flooding", answer: "Security Settings"),
Flashcard(question: " MAC Cloning/Spoofing", answer: "Attacker will modify MAC their address to match that of a legitimate device and gain access to a network they shouldn't have"),
Flashcard(question: " In MAC spoofing, communications in victim's MAC will be sent to the ___ instead, causing a DoS for the victim", answer: "Attacker"),
Flashcard(question: " DNS Poisoning", answer: "An attack that substitutes DNS addresses so that the computer is automatically redirected to an attacker's device."),
Flashcard(question: " The ___ takes precedent over any DNS queries", answer: "Host File"),
Flashcard(question: " Once attacker changes DNS IP address, any subsequent users who log into website will be responded to with the ___ IP address", answer: "Incorrect"),
Flashcard(question: " Domain Hijacking", answer: "An attack that changes the registration of a domain name without permission from the owner"),
Flashcard(question: " URL Hijacking", answer: "Redirecting a user to a fictitious website based on a misspelling of the URL. Also called typo squatting."),
Flashcard(question: " Domain Reputation", answer: "Protection for registered domains (email or web server) that provides monitoring and threat intelligence"),
Flashcard(question: " A ___ can be a smokescreen for something like DNS spoofing", answer: "DoS"),
Flashcard(question: " A friendly DoS can be caused by plugging in to the wrong cable and causing a ___ in your network", answer: "Loop"),
Flashcard(question: " Always turn on ___ to prevent layer 2 loops", answer: "STP"),
Flashcard(question: " DDoS", answer: "Large army of computers to bring down a service using something such as bandwidth spikes"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers often use ___ to perform a DDoS because it consists of thousands of computers", answer: "Botnets"),
Flashcard(question: " Asymmetric Threat", answer: "The attacker may have fewer resources than the victim, so they use more computers to overwhelm the victim"),
Flashcard(question: " DDoS Amplification", answer: "Take a small attack and have it arrive at the victim's machine as a much larger attack"),
Flashcard(question: " For DDoS amplification, the attacker needs to find open ___ and query them with a spoofed IP address", answer: "DNS Resolvers"),
Flashcard(question: " Once responses have grown in the DNS resolvers, they are all then sent to the ___ which can overwhelm it", answer: "Web Server"),
Flashcard(question: " Application DoS", answer: "An attack that causes a service to fail by exploiting a vulnerable application feature e.g. zip bomb"),
Flashcard(question: " Operational Technology DoS", answer: "Shutting down things such as power grids or manufacturing plands"),
Flashcard(question: " Because script is as fast as computer, attacker can have ___ functions find the vulnerable systems", answer: "Many Automated"),
Flashcard(question: " Windows PowerShell", answer: "Extends command line functionality to be able to manage almost every aspect of the operating system"),
Flashcard(question: " Powershell has a ___ function", answer: ".ps1"),
Flashcard(question: " Windows PowerShell uses ___", answer: "cmdlets"),
Flashcard(question: " Python", answer: ".py file extension, popular in many operating systems, and commonly used for cloud orchestration"),
Flashcard(question: " Shell Script", answer: "Used in Unix and Linux, flexible scripting environment, automates and extends command line"),
Flashcard(question: " Since everything in Linux or Unix is done at the ___ the shell script is perfect to automate attacks", answer: "Command Line"),
Flashcard(question: " Macros", answer: "Written specific to certain types of applications to make them easier to use, which can create vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " VBA (Visual Basic for Applications)", answer: "Programming languages used to implement macros and scripting in Office document automation"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers can target the ___ since VBA is connected to it", answer: "Operating System"),
Flashcard(question: " Threat Actor", answer: "An entity responsible for an event that has an impact on the safety of another entity"),
Flashcard(question: " APT (Advanced Persistent Threat)", answer: "A threat that is able to get into your network and stays there until you take it out"),
Flashcard(question: " An APT takes ___ days to be detected in North and South America and even longer in other places", answer: "71"),
Flashcard(question: " Insiders", answer: "Employers or contractors who work for organization, usually know things such as data center location"),
Flashcard(question: " Nation State", answer: "Usually with the government and in charge of national security, always external and many resources"),
Flashcard(question: " Hacktivist", answer: "Hacker with a purpose or goal against a third party, usually social change or political agenda"),
Flashcard(question: " Hacktivists are very focused on a ___", answer: "Single Message"),
Flashcard(question: " Script Kiddie", answer: "Focused on running very simple scripts to be able to gain access to someone's network"),
Flashcard(question: " Script kiddies throw ___ different scripts at a network hoping one of them will go in", answer: "Many"),
Flashcard(question: " Script kiddies are motivated by ___ (Hey I gained access to someone's network!)", answer: "Bragging Rights"),
Flashcard(question: " Organized Crime", answer: "A set of professional criminals motivated by money, very sophisticated and always external"),
Flashcard(question: " Shadow IT", answer: "You are performing your own IT functions without working with your internal IT department"),
Flashcard(question: " Shadow IT operators use their own equipment or procedures because they feel that the procedures of their company's IT department put up ___ to do their job", answer: "Roadblocks"),
Flashcard(question: " Competitors", answer: "Companies who want to take down a company through computer attacks and unethical means (eg. steal customer lists)"),
Flashcard(question: " Attack Vector", answer: "Method used by an attacker to gain access to a victim's network"),
Flashcard(question: " Direct Access Attack Vector", answer: "Physical access to a system; the reason we lock up data centers, (eg. transfer data onto flash drive)"),
Flashcard(question: " A form of direct access attack vector is to attach a ___ to a keyboard and see what everyone typed on it", answer: "Keylogger"),
Flashcard(question: " Wireless Attack Vectors", answer: "Wireless access to the system such as rogue access points or evil twins"),
Flashcard(question: " Email Attack Vectors", answer: "One of the largest and most successful attack vectors, easy to phish or attach malware"),
Flashcard(question: " Supply Chain Attack Vectors", answer: "Hackers try to compromise target by exploiting vulnerabilities in a third party vector"),
Flashcard(question: " Social Media Attack Vectors", answer: "Looking at social media account to gather information"),
Flashcard(question: " Removable Media Attack Vectors", answer: "Using something such as a USB drive to inject malicious software or gather files"),
Flashcard(question: " Cloud Attack Vectors", answer: "Viruses, email attachments, pop ups, or anything that can get data in the cloud"),
Flashcard(question: " Threat Intelligence", answer: "The process of investigating and collecting information about emerging threats and threat sources"),
Flashcard(question: " Open-Source Intelligence (OSINT)", answer: "Information that is readily available to the public and doesn't require any type of malicious activity to obtain"),
Flashcard(question: " Closed/Proprietary Intelligence", answer: "Compiled threat information that people are in business to make available to you for a cost"),
Flashcard(question: " Vulnerability Databases", answer: "Large databases that compile information coming from many different researchers"),
Flashcard(question: " Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE)", answer: "An online list of known vulnerabilities (and patches) to software, especially web servers. Sponsored by DHS and CISA"),
Flashcard(question: " U.S. National Vulnerability Database (NVD)", answer: "Summary of CVEs that you can browse to find vulnerabilities that may affect you"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ databases sometimes provide info that is classified but made available by the federal government", answer: "Public Threat Intelligence"),
Flashcard(question: " Private Threat Intelligence", answer: "Companies that share information especially organizations in the IT security industry"),
Flashcard(question: " CTA (Cyber Threat Intelligence)", answer: "Members upload the information they have about a particular threat, and it is evaluated and uploaded to the organization"),
Flashcard(question: " Automated Indicator Sharing (AIS)", answer: "Enables the exchange of cyber threat indicators, at machine speed, among the Federal Government"),
Flashcard(question: " STIX (Structured Threat Information eXpression)", answer: "Describes cyber threat information and includes motivation, capabilities, etc"),
Flashcard(question: " TAXII (Trusted Automated eXchange of Indicator Information)", answer: "Safely transfer the STIX data between organizations"),
Flashcard(question: " Dark Web", answer: "Overlay to existing internet that requires specialized software to be able to access"),
Flashcard(question: " The ___ can be used to find the activities and transactions of hacking groups and services", answer: "Dark Web"),
Flashcard(question: " IOC (Indicator of Compromise)", answer: "A sign that an asset or network has been attacked or is currently under attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Indicators of compromise include ___ amount of internet activity or ___ file hash values", answer: "Unusual Changed"),
Flashcard(question: " Predicative Analysis", answer: "Analyze very large amounts of data very quickly and find suspicious patterns"),
Flashcard(question: " Threat Maps", answer: "A real-time map of the computer security attacks that are going on at any given time"),
Flashcard(question: " File/Code Repositories", answer: "See what hackers are using to build their attacks, GitHub, private code can often be released public which is then used by hackers"),
Flashcard(question: " Threat Research", answer: "A never ending process; have to know your enemy and their tools of war"),
Flashcard(question: " Vendor Websites", answer: "The ones who wrote the software and know when problems are announced"),
Flashcard(question: " National Vulnerability Database (NVD)", answer: "The U.S. government repository of standards-based vulnerability management data"),
Flashcard(question: " It is common to supplement the NVD with ___ feeds from other organizations", answer: "Third Party"),
Flashcard(question: " Conferences", answer: "An in-person way to learn the latest of vulnerabilities and threats, usually from researchers"),
Flashcard(question: " Academic Journals", answer: "Research from professionals with cutting edge security analysis"),
Flashcard(question: " Request for Comments (RFC)", answer: "Documents are how standards and protocols are defined and published for all to see"),
Flashcard(question: " Local Industry Groups", answer: "Usually associations, a gathering of local peers to discuss local cybersecurity challenges"),
Flashcard(question: " Threat Feeds", answer: "Cybersecurity data feeds that provide information on the latest and most dangerous threats"),
Flashcard(question: " TTP (Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures)", answer: "Analysis of historical cyber-attacks and adversary actions and how they perform them"),
Flashcard(question: " Zero-Day Attacks", answer: "Attacks that exploit previously unknown vulnerabilities, so victims have no time to prepare or defend against the attacks"),
Flashcard(question: " Open Permissions", answer: "Information has been put onto the internet but no security has been applied to that data, easy for hackers to access"),
Flashcard(question: " Open permissions have become increasingly common with ___", answer: "Cloud Storage"),
Flashcard(question: " Unsecured Root Accounts", answer: "Unprotected accounts that give unfettered access to all resources, even worse if admin account"),
Flashcard(question: " Sometimes you can put too much information in an ___ message, and this info can be used against us", answer: "Error"),
Flashcard(question: " Weak Encryption", answer: "Encryption that is relatively easy or simple to decrypt without the encryption key, type of vulnerability"),
Flashcard(question: " TLS (Transport Layer Security)", answer: "We commonly use this protocol in our browsers to encrypt data, one of the most common vulnerability issues"),
Flashcard(question: " There are over ___ cipher suites in TLS", answer: "300"),
Flashcard(question: " Insecure Protocols", answer: "Some protocols aren't encrypted; all traffic sent in the clear ex. Telnet, FTP, SMTP, IMAP"),
Flashcard(question: " If you are not sure an application is sending information in the clear you can verify with a ___", answer: "Packet Capture"),
Flashcard(question: " If a packet capture is read in ___ then it is not being encrypted during transport", answer: "Plain English"),
Flashcard(question: " Encrypted Protocols", answer: "SSH, SFTP, IMAPS, etc. better than insecure protocols"),
Flashcard(question: " Wall of Sheep", answer: "A list of everybody communicating on the network in the clear along with the passwords"),
Flashcard(question: " Attackers know that some users don't change their ___ making them vulnerable", answer: "Default Settings"),
Flashcard(question: " Mirai Botnet", answer: "Takes advantage of default usernames and passwords to gain access to systems and take over for their own use"),
Flashcard(question: " To make things worse, the Mirai Botnet is now ___ so hackers can download and modify it for their own means", answer: "Open Source"),
Flashcard(question: " You have to ___ on the server so applications can talk to the server itself", answer: "Open Ports"),
Flashcard(question: " We often manage traffic flows with ___ which can allow or deny based on port number or application", answer: "Firewalls"),
Flashcard(question: " Improper Patch Management", answer: "Often centrally managed, can be very damaging if not up to date"),
Flashcard(question: " Legacy Platforms", answer: "Used to describe systems that are no longer being marketed or supported, can be a security concern"),
Flashcard(question: " IT security does not change because it is a ___", answer: "Third Party"),
Flashcard(question: " System Integration Risk", answer: "People who install systems have either virtual access to a system or physical (keyloggers, etc.)"),
Flashcard(question: " System integrators are a risk because they have access to the ___ without having to go through security protocols", answer: "Internal Network"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ are the only ones who can fix their products, so it is important to have vendor support", answer: "Vendors"),
Flashcard(question: " You can't always control security at a ___ location, which puts supply chains at risk", answer: "Third Party"),
Flashcard(question: " Outsourced Code Development", answer: "Contracting with third parties to assist the organization in the development and writing of a software program"),
Flashcard(question: " If data is stored at a third party encryption, we need to make sure all communications in and out are over an ___", answer: "Encrypted Channel"),
Flashcard(question: " In some cases losing ___ can be more damaging than losing money", answer: "Data"),
Flashcard(question: " Meow Attack", answer: "This attack overwrote data and wrote it with this word"),
Flashcard(question: " Identity Theft", answer: "A crime that involves someone pretending to be another person in order to steal money or obtain benefits"),
Flashcard(question: " Security breaches can result in heavy ___ of millions of dollars", answer: "Financial Loss"),
Flashcard(question: " Getting hacked impacts the ___ of an organization, resulting in stock drops and disclosures", answer: "Reputation"),
Flashcard(question: " The problem with intelligence data is that it is ___ so we can't respond until the attack occurs", answer: "Reactive"),
Flashcard(question: " Intelligence Fusion", answer: "Putting all the data into a massive database so you can pick out the most important pieces of data"),
Flashcard(question: " Fusing Data", answer: "Involves collecting intelligence, using outside sources, then analyzing big data"),
Flashcard(question: " Vulnerability Scanning", answer: "The act of scanning for weaknesses and susceptibilities in the network and on individual systems"),
Flashcard(question: " Port Scan", answer: "Sees which ports are open on a particular IP address to see what might not be secure"),
Flashcard(question: " You want to perform vulnerability scans from the perspective of the ___ (outside and inside)", answer: "Attacker"),
Flashcard(question: " Non-Intrusive Scans", answer: "Gather information, don't try to exploit a vulnerability"),
Flashcard(question: " Intrusive Scans", answer: "You'll try out the vulnerability to see if it works"),
Flashcard(question: " Non-Credentialed Scans", answer: "Run from the perspective of someone who does not have access to the remote device"),
Flashcard(question: " Credentialed Scan", answer: "Run under context of a valid account and are typically more accurate than non-credentialed scans"),
Flashcard(question: " Make sure ___ knows what's happening because a vulnerability scan could potentially crash the device", answer: "Everyone"),
Flashcard(question: " Application Scan", answer: "An automated test used to identify weaknesses in a software application like desktop"),
Flashcard(question: " Web Application Scan", answer: "Scans software on a web server for vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " CVSS (Common Vulnerability Scoring System)", answer: "Provides scoring of vulnerabilities on a scale of 1-10 so you can determine which ones are the most severe"),
Flashcard(question: " False Positive", answer: "A vulnerability is identified that doesn't really exist"),
Flashcard(question: " False Negative", answer: "A vulnerability that exists but was not detected"),
Flashcard(question: " Configuration Review", answer: "To verify the operating condition and the effectiveness of its security configuration and rule sets"),
Flashcard(question: " SIEM (Security Information and Event Management)", answer: "Logging of security events and information onto the central database"),
Flashcard(question: " Syslog", answer: "Sends system status messages from several different devices to a central server for monitoring and review"),
Flashcard(question: " Syslog needs a ___ of space since it is collecting data from many different devices", answer: "Large Amount"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Inputs", answer: "Server authentication attempts, VPN connections, firewall session logs etc. that should be in SIEM"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ are a common part of SIEM data", answer: "Packet Captures"),
Flashcard(question: " SOC (Security Operations Center)", answer: "The location where security professionals monitor and protect critical information assets in an organization, can monitor SIEM data"),
Flashcard(question: " There is a constant ___ in a SIEM", answer: "Information Flow"),
Flashcard(question: " SIEMs have a ___ that rolls up information into a mode that can be easily identified", answer: "Dashboard"),
Flashcard(question: " Big Data Analytics", answer: "The ability to look through large amounts of very diverse data and identify patterns normally invisible to a human being"),
Flashcard(question: " UEBA (User and Entity Behavior Analytics)", answer: "A system that can provide automated identification of suspicious activity by user accounts and computer hosts"),
Flashcard(question: " Sentiment Analysis", answer: "Examines how public views a particular organization; if public opinion is bad, it tends to attract hackers"),
Flashcard(question: " SOAR (Security Orchestration, Automation, and Response)", answer: "Takes manual and tedious security processes and automates them so they can be done at computer speed"),
Flashcard(question: " Orchestration", answer: "Using many tools together such as firewalls, account management, and email filters"),
Flashcard(question: " Penetration Test", answer: "An authorized attempt to break into the organization's information system by exploiting vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " Rules of Engagement", answer: "Penetration test document that defines purpose and makes everyone aware of parameters"),
Flashcard(question: " The rules of engagement also lists the ___ of the devices that are in scope for the penetration test", answer: "IP Addresses"),
Flashcard(question: " Blind Test", answer: "Pentester knows nothing about the systems they are testing on"),
Flashcard(question: " Known Environment", answer: "In a penetration test where tester knows everything about device"),
Flashcard(question: " Partially Known Environment", answer: "Mix of known and unknown, may be contracting with third party who runs pentests on key systems"),
Flashcard(question: " It is important that the person performing the penetration test has permission to ___ on that system", answer: "Exploit Vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " A good penetration tests tries many different ___", answer: "Vulnerability Types"),
Flashcard(question: " Lateral Movement", answer: "Moving from device to device within a network during penetration test"),
Flashcard(question: " It's very common to have stronger security on the ___ of the network", answer: "Perimeter"),
Flashcard(question: " Persistence", answer: "Making sure there is a way back into the account after the penetration test is done"),
Flashcard(question: " Pivot Point", answer: "Gaining access to a system and using that system to get to any other system on the network"),
Flashcard(question: " After penetration test, all systems need to be ___ to how they were before the test", answer: "Reverted Back"),
Flashcard(question: " Bug Bounty", answer: "Reward scheme operated by software and web services vendors for reporting vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " Reconaissance", answer: "Footprinting all of the devices in an organization to understand its security measures"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Map", answer: "Part of recon, used to identify routers, networks, and remote sites"),
Flashcard(question: " Passive Footprinting", answer: "Gathering information about a target without direct interaction using open sources (eg. social media)"),
Flashcard(question: " OSINT (Open Source Intelligence)", answer: "Find information on anyone or anything, not related to OSS"),
Flashcard(question: " Wardriving of Warflying", answer: "Combining WiFi analysis with GPS locations to know where a wireless network might be, using car or drone"),
Flashcard(question: " Active Footprinting", answer: "Effort is one that requires the attacker to touch the device, network, or resource (eg. ping and port scans)"),
Flashcard(question: " In cybersecurity, analysts become an expert in their ___", answer: "Niche"),
Flashcard(question: " Red Team", answer: "The offense team, usually hired attackers or ethical hackers"),
Flashcard(question: " Blue Team", answer: "The defense team that protects the data, day-to-day operational security"),
Flashcard(question: " Purple Team", answer: "Red and blue teams working together so they can share information instead of compete"),
Flashcard(question: " White Team", answer: "Manages interactions between red and blue teams, enforces rules, basically refs"),
Flashcard(question: " The only constant with cybersecurity is ___", answer: "Change"),
Flashcard(question: " Configuration Management", answer: "The process of ensuring that only authorized changes are made to a system and they are modified and documented"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Diagram", answer: "Map of which devices are connected to each other, sometimes diagram of what racks they are in"),
Flashcard(question: " In a data center, equipment can be spread across many different racks but are still ___ via wires under the floor", answer: "Connected"),
Flashcard(question: " Baseline Configuration", answer: "Security of an application environment must be well defined and all app instances will follow it"),
Flashcard(question: " Integrity Measurements Check", answer: "Checks to see if all details in your documentation match what is running in that particular application"),
Flashcard(question: " For configuration management, create a ___ that is easily understood by everyone so they can better complete tasks", answer: "Standard"),
Flashcard(question: " IP Schema", answer: "A way of knowing which IP addresses are used at which locations to avoid confusion"),
Flashcard(question: " Protecting Data", answer: "A primary job task in cybersecurity"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Sovereignty", answer: "The laws associated with data depending on where it resides; laws may prohibit where it is stored"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Obfuscation", answer: "Data transformation that makes it difficult for a human to recognize the original data, such as x's on receipts"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Encryption", answer: "The process of making data from plaintext to ciphertext to make it unreadable"),
Flashcard(question: " If you have the ___ you can convert ciphertext to plaintext and vice-versa", answer: "Proper Key"),
Flashcard(question: " Confusion", answer: "The info we are encrypting and putting into ciphertext is very different than original info in plaintext"),
Flashcard(question: " Diffusion", answer: "If you change one piece of info in the plaintext, the resulting cipher text will be dramatically different"),
Flashcard(question: " Data-At-Rest", answer: "Data that is stored on a storage device, needs to be encrypted to be protected"),
Flashcard(question: " Data-In-Transmit", answer: "Data going between switches, routers, and devices, not as much protection because it is travelling"),
Flashcard(question: " Data-In-Use", answer: "Data actively processing in the memory, such as RAM, GPU registers, and cache"),
Flashcard(question: " Data-in-use is almost always ___ making it a preferred place for attackers", answer: "Decrypted"),
Flashcard(question: " Tokenization", answer: "Replacing sensitive data with a completely different set of data"),
Flashcard(question: " IRM (Information Rights Management)", answer: "Restricts data from unauthorized persons, (eg. PDF that won't allow you to copy and paste)"),
Flashcard(question: " DLP (Data Loss Prevention)", answer: "Looks in several different locations and protects data from prying eyes"),
Flashcard(question: " Endpoint DLP Solution", answer: "Resides on our local workstations and devices; examines everything being transferred in and out of device"),
Flashcard(question: " DLP on a workstation can allow or disallow access to data that's being stored on a ___", answer: "USB Drive"),
Flashcard(question: " Cloud-Based DLP", answer: "Able to look for all traffic going through the cloud to see if predefined data strings exist within data flows"),
Flashcard(question: " We need DLP on our ___ to block any information classified as sensitive", answer: "Email Systems"),
Flashcard(question: " Offsite Backup", answer: "Organization-owned site or third party facility"),
Flashcard(question: " Offsite Recovery", answer: "Sending critical data off the main site as a disaster plan"),
Flashcard(question: " An incidence response plan consists of ___ to help us know how to identify and respond to an attack", answer: "Documented Processes"),
Flashcard(question: " SSL/TLS Inspection", answer: "Commonly used to view information within incoming and outgoing encrypted SSL/TLS packets"),
Flashcard(question: " SSL/TLS inspection relies on ___", answer: "Trust"),
Flashcard(question: " The trust of SSL comes from a list of ___ embedded within the browser of your device", answer: "CAs"),
Flashcard(question: " Your browser does not trust a website unless a ___ has signed the web server's encryption certificate", answer: "CA"),
Flashcard(question: " SSL/TLS Proxy", answer: "Inserted in the middle of the conversation and can decrypt the data flow to check for malicious content"),
Flashcard(question: " Hashing can also be a ___", answer: "Digital Signature"),
Flashcard(question: " To protect API you should ___ the login page", answer: "Secure"),
Flashcard(question: " On-Path Attack", answer: "Intercept and modify API messages, replay API commands"),
Flashcard(question: " API Injection", answer: "Get into middle of conversation, see how API operates, then put own data into API flows"),
Flashcard(question: " Authentication", answer: "Limit API access to legitimate users over secure protocols"),
Flashcard(question: " Authorization", answer: "API should not allow extended access, each user has a limited role"),
Flashcard(question: " WAF (Web Application Firewall)", answer: "Can apply rules to API communication"),
Flashcard(question: " When disaster happens you need to move everything to an ___ site", answer: "Alternate"),
Flashcard(question: " You need processes and procedures for moving to the recovery site, and also for moving back to the ___", answer: "Original Location"),
Flashcard(question: " Hot Site", answer: "An exact replica of what we are running in our production environment"),
Flashcard(question: " Because the recovery and main sites are a ___ it is easy to flip the switch to move the data between each", answer: "Mirror Image"),
Flashcard(question: " Cold Site", answer: "No hardware, empty building which means you need to bring the data with you"),
Flashcard(question: " Warm Site", answer: "Big room with rack space so you can set up the hardware in a short amount of time"),
Flashcard(question: " Honeypot", answer: "A system designed to look very attractive so that attackers fall for it and get trapped"),
Flashcard(question: " With honeypots the attacker is probably a ___", answer: "Machine"),
Flashcard(question: " The honeypot needs to look and feel like a ___ so that the attacker does not know it is a honeypot", answer: "Real System"),
Flashcard(question: " Honeynet", answer: "Multiple honeypots where you can begin gathering information from multiple sources"),
Flashcard(question: " Honeyfile", answer: "Bait within the honeypot that you hope the attacker will go after"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ can take big data and identify patterns and info within that large data source", answer: "Machine Learning"),
Flashcard(question: " Machine learning needs to be fed with ___ (malware, viruses, etc.) so it knows what to look for", answer: "Actual Data"),
Flashcard(question: " Fake Telemetry", answer: "Inserted into data to get a machine to think that the malware is actually good"),
Flashcard(question: " DNS Sinkhole", answer: "A DNS server that gives out incorrect info about the IP address of a particular FQDN"),
Flashcard(question: " FQDN (Fully Qualified Domain Name)", answer: "A host name plus domain name that uniquely identifies a computer or location on a network"),
Flashcard(question: " IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service)", answer: "Cloud-hosted provider of virtualized servers and networks, eg. web server"),
Flashcard(question: " SaaS (Software as a Service)", answer: "Pay for software as you use it. Not installed locally, instead it is hosted software e.g. Google Docs"),
Flashcard(question: " PaaS (Platform as a Service)", answer: "Cloud-based virtual server(s). These virtualized platforms give programmers tools needed to deploy, administer, and maintain a Web application."),
Flashcard(question: " XaaS (Anything as a Service)", answer: "A broad description of any type of service provided over the cloud"),
Flashcard(question: " On Premises", answer: "Cloud model where all technology needed to run an application would be on systems in your premises"),
Flashcard(question: " MSP (Managed Service Provider)", answer: "Provides network connectivity, disaster recovery, etc to make sure your systems are to scale"),
Flashcard(question: " MSSP (Managed Security Service Provider)", answer: "Focuses on IT security such as firewall or patch management"),
Flashcard(question: " Off Premises", answer: "Servers are located in the building of a third party"),
Flashcard(question: " Public", answer: "Cloud service available to anyone"),
Flashcard(question: " Community", answer: "Several organizations pool resources together to create a shared set of cloud services"),
Flashcard(question: " Private", answer: "Cloud service internal in your data center that only you have access to"),
Flashcard(question: " Hybrid", answer: "Cloud service that has both public and private cloud models"),
Flashcard(question: " Since the cloud is ___ it is difficult to protect data", answer: "Far"),
Flashcard(question: " IoT (Internet of Things)", answer: "A computing concept that describes where everyday physical objects are connected to the Internet"),
Flashcard(question: " Edge Computing", answer: "Applications that are running and their data all occur on local system and don't have to connect to internet"),
Flashcard(question: " Fog Computing", answer: "Allows us to send some data into the cloud for processing without requiring all the data be in one place"),
Flashcard(question: " Thin Client", answer: "Single device that allows us to connect keyboard, mouse, and monitor and then connect to desktop running in cloud"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtualization", answer: "Running multiple operating systems on a single physical piece of hardware"),
Flashcard(question: " Hypervisor", answer: "Manages all the different operating systems running on a computer"),
Flashcard(question: " Containerization", answer: "Run multiple applications in the same sandbox, but not have separate host operating systems for each one"),
Flashcard(question: " Monolithic", answer: "A single application that contains all the decision making processes and does everything"),
Flashcard(question: " API (Application Programming Interface)", answer: "Breaks up an application into individual services"),
Flashcard(question: " Microservice", answer: "A small reusable chunk of code that performs a specific function that is a part of a larger application"),
Flashcard(question: " Serverless Architecture", answer: "Applications are separated into autonomous functions; remove operating system from the equation"),
Flashcard(question: " Stateless Compute Container", answer: "Processors designed to respond to API requests; used for serverless architecture"),
Flashcard(question: " VPC (Virtual Private Cloud)", answer: "A pool of resources created in a public cloud"),
Flashcard(question: " Transit Gateway", answer: "Connect thousands of VPC and on-premises networks together"),
Flashcard(question: " Resource Policies", answer: "Assigning permissions to cloud resources, can be difficult since the cloud is always running"),
Flashcard(question: " SIAM (Service Integration and Management)", answer: "Consolidates all the different cloud services into one single management interface"),
Flashcard(question: " Infrastructure as Code", answer: "Defines servers, network, and applications as a series of code"),
Flashcard(question: " Infrastructure as a code is an important concept for ___", answer: "Cloud Computing"),
Flashcard(question: " SDN (Software Defined Networking)", answer: "Separating functionality of networking devices into two functional planes of operation (control and data)"),
Flashcard(question: " Control Plane", answer: "Handles management and ongoing configuration of the device"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Plane", answer: "Part of device that handles the actual operation"),
Flashcard(question: " SDN devices are ___ managed", answer: "Centrally"),
Flashcard(question: " SDN follows a set of ___", answer: "Open Standards"),
Flashcard(question: " SDV (Software Defined Visibility)", answer: "Allows us to deploy firewalls and security devices while understanding what type of data is flowing between systems"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtual Machine Sprawl", answer: "The widespread proliferation of virtual machines without proper oversight or management"),
Flashcard(question: " Everything happening on a virtual machine happens within because it is ___", answer: "Self-Contained"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtual Machine Escape", answer: "When a user (or malware) is able to break out of a VM's isolation (or lack thereof) and gain access to the hosting computer"),
Flashcard(question: " Sandbox", answer: "Isolated testing environment that can be used by developers to test aspects of app they are developing"),
Flashcard(question: " Developer", answer: "Writes code and tests aspects of its functionality"),
Flashcard(question: " Quality Assurance", answer: "People who verify application features are working and can also test new features"),
Flashcard(question: " Staging", answer: "Application is tested in a real world environment"),
Flashcard(question: " Security Baseline", answer: "Something all application instances must follow, usually needs frequent updates"),
Flashcard(question: " Integrity Check", answer: "Makes sure the app's production environment matches requirements on original security baseline"),
Flashcard(question: " Provisioning", answer: "The process of deploying servers and making them available"),
Flashcard(question: " Scalability", answer: "How well a system can scale up, or adapt to the increased demands of growth"),
Flashcard(question: " Elasticity", answer: "The ability to increase or decrease available resources for an application based on workload"),
Flashcard(question: " Orchestration", answer: "The key to cloud computing, automates provisioning and deprovisioning of applications"),
Flashcard(question: " Deprovisioning", answer: "Completely removing any remnants of an app from running in your environment"),
Flashcard(question: " Stored Procedures", answer: "A group of SQL statements that execute as a whole, similar to a mini-program. Developers use them to prevent SQL injection attacks"),
Flashcard(question: " Stored procedures are stored on the ___ itself", answer: "Database Server"),
Flashcard(question: " Obfuscation", answer: "Make something normally understandable difficult to understand"),
Flashcard(question: " Code Reuse", answer: "Common for developers, use old code to make new applications"),
Flashcard(question: " If the old code has security vulnerabilities, reusing it can spread them to ___", answer: "Multiple Applications"),
Flashcard(question: " Dead Code", answer: "Put into the application, processing logic but the results of that logic aren't used anywhere else on the app"),
Flashcard(question: " Input Validation", answer: "A programming process that verifies data is valid before using it"),
Flashcard(question: " Normalization", answer: "Check and correct all input into an application"),
Flashcard(question: " Server-Side Validation", answer: "Code on the server looks through data to make sure the input has been done correctly"),
Flashcard(question: " Client-Side Validation", answer: "The end-user application will verify the input on the client's machine before sending to the server"),
Flashcard(question: " Server-side validation is considered ___ than client-side", answer: "Safer"),
Flashcard(question: " Buffer Overflow", answer: "A technique for crashing by sending too much data to a section of the computer's memory"),
Flashcard(question: " SDK (software development kit)", answer: "Written by someone else, extends functionality of programming language"),
Flashcard(question: " Version Control", answer: "A process to keep track of what changes were made to what files so that a specific version can be referred to and improvements in multiple versions can be merged together."),
Flashcard(question: " Software Diversity", answer: "People might all run the OS or app the same but each person has a unique final binary file"),
Flashcard(question: " Continuous Integration", answer: "App is constantly updated and code is merged into central repository several times a day"),
Flashcard(question: " Continuous Delivery", answer: "Automate the testing and release of security application, then wait for us to click a button to deploy"),
Flashcard(question: " Continuous Deployment", answer: "Entire testing, release and deployment process of an app is automated"),
Flashcard(question: " Directory Services", answer: "Central database that stores usernames, passwords, computers, devices connected to network"),
Flashcard(question: " Directory service database is distributed across ___ that all communicate with each other", answer: "Multiple Services"),
Flashcard(question: " Directory services require a ___", answer: "Single Authentication"),
Flashcard(question: " Federation", answer: "A way to allow someone to authenticate to your network using credentials stored with a third party (eg. log in with facebook)"),
Flashcard(question: " Attestation", answer: "Have the system prove that hardware connecting into your network is actually yours"),
Flashcard(question: " Remote Attestation", answer: "Remote system verifies files are the same and makes sure that the system is safe"),
Flashcard(question: " SMS (Short Message Service)", answer: "Short text messages, typically fewer than 300 characters"),
Flashcard(question: " Push Notification", answer: "Allows an application to notify a user of new messages or events, even when the user is not actively using the app"),
Flashcard(question: " A ___ token generator provides coding and is a useful authentication factor", answer: "Pseudo-Random"),
Flashcard(question: " TOTP (Time-Based One-Time Password)", answer: "Pseudo random number will be available as a login credential for usually about 30 seconds before changing"),
Flashcard(question: " HOTP (HMAC-based one-time password)", answer: "For authentication, you have a number you would use once then never use again"),
Flashcard(question: " You can also use a ___ to have someone tell you an authentication code", answer: "Phone Call"),
Flashcard(question: " Static Codes", answer: "codes that do not change over time such as a PIN"),
Flashcard(question: " Gait Analysis", answer: "A biometric factor that identifies someone based on how they walk"),
Flashcard(question: " Vascular Scanner", answer: "Biometric factor that identifies people based on layout of their veins"),
Flashcard(question: " FAR (False Acceptance Rate)", answer: "How often an unauthorized user will be approved by biometrics"),
Flashcard(question: " FRR (False Rejection Rate)", answer: "How often authorized users are rejected by the system, usually because it is too sensitive"),
Flashcard(question: " CER (Crossover Error Rate)", answer: "The rate where false rejection rate and the false acceptance rate are equal, usually by dialing both down"),
Flashcard(question: " AAA Framework", answer: "Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting"),
Flashcard(question: " A ___ authentication involves a centralized platform managed by a third party", answer: "Cloud-Based"),
Flashcard(question: " An ___ authentication system is on a local data center with internal monitoring and management", answer: "On-Premises"),
Flashcard(question: " Authentication Factor", answer: "Comparing a characteristic to what you know is associated with an individual"),
Flashcard(question: " Authentication Attribute", answer: "May not be directly associated with individual, but can include with other authentication factors to prove someone's identity"),
Flashcard(question: " Multi factor authentication uses something you ___, ____ and ___", answer: "Know Have Are"),
Flashcard(question: " Somewhere You Are", answer: "An authentication factor indicating location, often using geolocation technologies"),
Flashcard(question: " Something You Can Do", answer: "Authentication based on how you do things such as a signature"),
Flashcard(question: " Something You Exhibit", answer: "Authentication factor based on unique trait such as how you type of walk"),
Flashcard(question: " Redundancy", answer: "How we duplicate parts of a system so that it is always up and running"),
Flashcard(question: " Geographic Dispersal", answer: "Moving technologies to several different areas in case a disaster happens in the local area"),
Flashcard(question: " Multipath Input/Output", answer: "Allows us to create other routes on the network that we can use to work around problems we might have"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID (Redundant Array of Independent Disks)", answer: "Using multiple drives within a single array, so if you lose data on one you can pull data from the others"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID 1 (Mirroring)", answer: "Two drives are used in unison, and all data is written to both drives, giving you an extra copy of the data, in the case that one drive fails"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID 5 (Striping With Parity)", answer: "Putting pieces of info on separate physical drives and putting some equivalent info on a final physical drive"),
Flashcard(question: " Load Balancer", answer: "Balances inbound and outbound connections to applications or service endpoints by choosing which servers to use"),
Flashcard(question: " NIC Teaming", answer: "Allows us to use primary and standby connections in a server simultaneously and aggregate bandwidth between them"),
Flashcard(question: " NICs talk to each other over a ___ connection", answer: "Multicast"),
Flashcard(question: " Port Aggregation", answer: "Joining multiple network device ports together for increased bandwidth and redundancy"),
Flashcard(question: " UPS (Uninterruptible Power Supply)", answer: "A device that provides backup power when the electrical power fails or drops to an unacceptable voltage level"),
Flashcard(question: " Offline/Standby", answer: "A UPS that is not normally enabled unless power is lost"),
Flashcard(question: " Line-Interactive", answer: "A UPS where if power is slowly diminishing it can slowly ramp up the power provided by the batteries"),
Flashcard(question: " Online/Double Conversion", answer: "UPS that always provides power and has no switching process when power goes out"),
Flashcard(question: " Generator", answer: "Long term power backup that can keep power running for days or weeks, uses fuel"),
Flashcard(question: " Power Redundancy", answer: "Having backup power sources in case the primary one fails"),
Flashcard(question: " If there are plugs in power sources on both sides of the power unit, then each source provides ___ of the power", answer: "0.5"),
Flashcard(question: " Hot Swappable", answer: "The feature of a component that allows it to be installed or removed without disrupting operations"),
Flashcard(question: " PDU (Power Distribution Unit)", answer: "Provides multiple power sources, such as a strip with multiple plug outlets"),
Flashcard(question: " SAN (Storage Area Network)", answer: "A specialized network of high-speed storage devices with built-in redundancy"),
Flashcard(question: " SAN Snapshot", answer: "Take data from one SAN, take exact makeup of data, and copy that data to a separate SAN"),
Flashcard(question: " VM Replication", answer: "Update one virtual machine and copy that update to all the other virtual machines"),
Flashcard(question: " Archive Attribute", answer: "Set when a file is modified, can access advanced options for a file"),
Flashcard(question: " Full Backup", answer: "Take everything in the operating system and save it"),
Flashcard(question: " Incremental Backup", answer: "Occurs after full backup, will back up all files that have changed since the last one"),
Flashcard(question: " Differential Backup", answer: "Occurs after full backup, but only files that are backed up are ones that have changed since last full backup"),
Flashcard(question: " For full restoration, you need every ___ and ___ backup that has occurred", answer: "Full Incremental"),
Flashcard(question: " Magnetic Tape", answer: "Sequential storage and can be from 100GB to several TB in storage"),
Flashcard(question: " Disk", answer: "Faster than tapes and can duplicate and compress data"),
Flashcard(question: " Copy", answer: "An exact duplicate of a system at a particular point in time"),
Flashcard(question: " NAS (Network Attached Storage)", answer: "Provides access to large storage array that's connected over the network"),
Flashcard(question: " A NAS is ___ meaning if you have to change any portion of a file on it, you have to rewrite the entire file", answer: "File-Level Access"),
Flashcard(question: " SAN (Storage Area Network)", answer: "Configured to look like a separate storage drive on your system, efficient reading and writing"),
Flashcard(question: " A SAN provides ___ so if you need to change a single portion of a large file, you only need to change that portion on the disk", answer: "Block-Level Access"),
Flashcard(question: " Image Backup", answer: "Backup everything on a computer and create an exact replica of the entire file system"),
Flashcard(question: " Offline Backup", answer: "Backing up to local devices on a fast and secure channel"),
Flashcard(question: " Online Backup", answer: "Constantly accessible, usually to a third party or cloud-based service, like cloud storage"),
Flashcard(question: " Non-Persistence", answer: "The way the cloud is always in motion and particular services are usually never permanent"),
Flashcard(question: " Snapshot", answer: "Captures current configuration and data so if you want to recreate that instance later you can"),
Flashcard(question: " High Availability", answer: "Having devices that are always on and always available, more costly"),
Flashcard(question: " Usually in the order of restoration you restore the ___ first in order to restore the application", answer: "Database"),
Flashcard(question: " By using ___ of technology you can implement multiple security devices to better protect your system", answer: "Diversity"),
Flashcard(question: " Embedded System", answer: "Hardware and software designed for a specific function with a single task in mind (eg. traffic light controllers)"),
Flashcard(question: " SoC (System On a Chip)", answer: "Has multiple components on a single chip that handles multiple functions"),
Flashcard(question: " The downside to SoC is that it is difficult to upgrade ___", answer: "Hardware"),
Flashcard(question: " FPGA (Field-Programmable Gate Array)", answer: "Integrated circuit that you can program after the device is manufactured and shipping"),
Flashcard(question: " SCADA (Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition System)", answer: "Found in places with large amount of industrial equipment, used to modify configuration of equipment"),
Flashcard(question: " IoT (Internet of Things)", answer: "Devices that can be connected to many different types of systems in our homes and businesses"),
Flashcard(question: " VoIP (Voice Over Internet Protocol)", answer: "This technology is used to make telephone calls via the Internet usually at a cheaper cost, replaced analog phone lines"),
Flashcard(question: " It's common for HVAC to have a ___ that monitors all of the HVAC for the facility", answer: "Computer"),
Flashcard(question: " MFD (Multifunction Device)", answer: "Device that can do several things (eg. printer with scan, copy, fax, etc.)"),
Flashcard(question: " RTOS (Real Time Operating System)", answer: "Designed to work on a very deterministic schedule, eg. anti lock brakes on vehicles"),
Flashcard(question: " 5G can get speeds up to ___ per second", answer: "10 GB"),
Flashcard(question: " SIM (Subscriber Identity Module)", answer: "A small smart card that contains programming and information for small devices such as cell phones."),
Flashcard(question: " IMSI (International Mobile Subscriber Identity)", answer: "A unique number that represents the actual user associated with a particular SIM card"),
Flashcard(question: " Narrowband", answer: "Allowing communication across a very narrow range of frequencies; over longer distance, conserve freq. use"),
Flashcard(question: " Many ___ devices can communicate over long distances with narrowband", answer: "IoT"),
Flashcard(question: " Baseband", answer: "Using a single frequency to be able to communicate, generally single cable such as fiber or copper"),
Flashcard(question: " Baseband uses ___ of the bandwidth on that connection", answer: "All"),
Flashcard(question: " ZigBee", answer: "Alternative to WiFi and Bluetooth, communicates with IoT devices over longer distances using less power"),
Flashcard(question: " Mesh Network", answer: "Every device is connected directly to every other device in the network"),
Flashcard(question: " An issue with embedded systems is they usually run on a device that is not a ___ computer", answer: "Fully Capable"),
Flashcard(question: " Since embedded systems are out in the field, they might not have direct access to ___", answer: "Power Sources"),
Flashcard(question: " For embedded systems it is difficult to change or modify ___ features", answer: "Cryptography"),
Flashcard(question: " Embedded devices usually cannot add on an ___ functionality; they do one thing very well", answer: "Additional"),
Flashcard(question: " Access Control Vestibule", answer: "All doors can be locked or unlocked; opening one door causes others to lock"),
Flashcard(question: " Alarm", answer: "Circuit, duress or motion-based, used to inform of unauthorized access"),
Flashcard(question: " Industrial Camouflage", answer: "Concealing an important facility behind what is normally seen in a particular area"),
Flashcard(question: " One of the most reliable physical security features are ___", answer: "Security Guards"),
Flashcard(question: " Two-Person Integrity", answer: "Must have at least two people in the facility at all times, to monitor one another's actions"),
Flashcard(question: " Biometrics usually store a ___ of your fingerprint instead of the actual thing", answer: "Mathematical Representation"),
Flashcard(question: " Cable Locks", answer: "Used to secure portable computers, external hard drives, and other portable pieces of hardware to a table or other object"),
Flashcard(question: " USB Data Blocker", answer: "Hardware plug to prevent malicious data transfer when a device is plugged into a USB charging point"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ is a bad fire suppressant in cybersecurity because there is electronic equipment", answer: "Water"),
Flashcard(question: " Faraday Cage", answer: "A metallic enclosure that prevents the entry or escape of an electromagnetic field"),
Flashcard(question: " Screened Subnet", answer: "Formerly DMZ, uses firewall to prevent access to internal network"),
Flashcard(question: " PDS (Protected Distribution System)", answer: "Secured system of cable management to ensure that the wired network remains free from eavesdropping, tapping, data emanations, and other threats"),
Flashcard(question: " Air Gap", answer: "Separation between networks; prevents access between secure network and insecure network"),
Flashcard(question: " Most environments are on a ___ network", answer: "Shared"),
Flashcard(question: " There are extensive ___ in data centers since they generate a lot of heat", answer: "Cooling Systems"),
Flashcard(question: " Data centers have ___ and ___ aisles to blow air from the floor to conserve energy keeping equipment cool", answer: "Cold Hot"),
Flashcard(question: " Certificate of Destruction", answer: "Provided by a third party confirming they destroyed all the data or hardware"),
Flashcard(question: " Purge Data", answer: "Remove a single file or a section of data from an existing data store"),
Flashcard(question: " Wipe Data", answer: "Unrecoverable removal of data on a storage device"),
Flashcard(question: " Plaintext", answer: "An unencrypted message; in the clear"),
Flashcard(question: " Ciphertext", answer: "Encrypted message"),
Flashcard(question: " Cipher", answer: "The algorithm(s) needed to encrypt and decrypt a message"),
Flashcard(question: " Cryptanalysis", answer: "The study and practice of finding weaknesses in ciphers"),
Flashcard(question: " Key", answer: "Information added to the cipher to be able to encrypt plain text"),
Flashcard(question: " Key Stretching", answer: "A technique that strengthens potentially weak cryptographic keys, such as passwords or passphrases"),
Flashcard(question: " bcrypt uses the ___ cipher", answer: "Blowfish"),
Flashcard(question: " Key Stretching Library", answer: "Can generate hashes and other key stretching techniques so you don't start from scratch"),
Flashcard(question: " Lightweight Cryptography", answer: "Provides cryptographic functions without having a high end CPU or using a lot of power"),
Flashcard(question: " NIST", answer: "Dedicated to finding most amount of cryptography using the least amount of power"),
Flashcard(question: " Homomorphic Encryption (HE)", answer: "Performs calculations of data while it is still encrypted, and save results without decrypting it"),
Flashcard(question: " Symmetric Encryption", answer: "Uses one key to encrypt and decrypt"),
Flashcard(question: " Symmetric encryption is like carrying a key in a ___", answer: "Locked Case"),
Flashcard(question: " Symmetric and asymmetric encryptions are often ___", answer: "Combined"),
Flashcard(question: " Asymmetric Encryption", answer: "Two keys are used; one key encodes the message, and the other key decodes the message"),
Flashcard(question: " Only the ___ key can decrypt data encrypted with the ___ key", answer: "Private Public"),
Flashcard(question: " Key Generation", answer: "The process of creating a public and private key simultaneously, lots of number randomization"),
Flashcard(question: " Public key is used to change plaintext to ___", answer: "Ciphertext"),
Flashcard(question: " Only the ___ can decrypt the ciphertext back to plaintext", answer: "Private Key"),
Flashcard(question: " You can combine public and private keys to create a ___ key", answer: "Symmetric"),
Flashcard(question: " Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC)", answer: "An algorithm that uses elliptic curves instead of prime numbers to compute keys"),
Flashcard(question: " Hashes are a ___ meaning once you apply them to data, you can't go back and recreate the data", answer: "One-Way Trip"),
Flashcard(question: " Non Repudiation", answer: "The process of proving that a user performed an action"),
Flashcard(question: " Collision", answer: "In hashing, where two different inputs have the same hashing output"),
Flashcard(question: " MD5", answer: "The hashing function that had a collision problem; don't use"),
Flashcard(question: " Digital Signature", answer: "Allow us to send info to another party and have them confirm that what they got was the exact info we sent"),
Flashcard(question: " Digital signatures are signed with the ___ of the user", answer: "Private Key"),
Flashcard(question: " Digital signatures are verified with the ___", answer: "Public Key"),
Flashcard(question: " Encryption Key", answer: "Used to encrypt and decrypt data, the one thing people don't know"),
Flashcard(question: " A ___ encryption key tends to be more secure", answer: "Larger"),
Flashcard(question: " For symmetric encryption we tend to see keys that are ___ or larger", answer: "128-Bit"),
Flashcard(question: " Asymmetric encryption keys tend to be ___ or larger", answer: "3072 Bits"),
Flashcard(question: " An ___ key exchange is where you don't use the internet to send a key, you use phone, courier, in-person, etc.", answer: "Out-of-Band"),
Flashcard(question: " An ___ key exchange is sent over the internet with additional encryption", answer: "In-Band"),
Flashcard(question: " You can use ___ to encrypt the symmetric key inside of it", answer: "Asymmetric Encryption"),
Flashcard(question: " Session Key", answer: "Key that is used only once before being discarded"),
Flashcard(question: " Diffie-Helman Key Exchange", answer: "Each person has a private key, and they'd both combine other user's public key with their own private key to create identical symmetric keys"),
Flashcard(question: " A web servers ___, if accessed, can rebuild everything and capture all the data", answer: "Private Key"),
Flashcard(question: " PFS (Perfect Forward Secrecy)", answer: "Changes encryption process so you're not using the same private key every time"),
Flashcard(question: " ECDHE (Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman Ephemeral)", answer: "Keys are created to transfer a single session, and keys are no longer used after session is over"),
Flashcard(question: " Obfuscation", answer: "The action of making something obscure, unclear, or unintelligible"),
Flashcard(question: " Obfuscation is often used with ___", answer: "Source Code"),
Flashcard(question: " Steganography", answer: "A field within cryptography; uses images to hide data"),
Flashcard(question: " Cover Text", answer: "Container that has steganography message inside of it"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ steganography embeds messages in TCP packets", answer: "Network Based"),
Flashcard(question: " Audio Steganography", answer: "The user embeds the hidden messages in a digital sound format"),
Flashcard(question: " Video Steganography", answer: "Hidden in video files, can store more information"),
Flashcard(question: " Quantum Computing", answer: "Uses the principles of quantum physics to represent data and perform operations on these data"),
Flashcard(question: " Classical Mechanics", answer: "Uses bits (0s and 1s)"),
Flashcard(question: " Quantum Bit (Qubit)", answer: "Exist somewhere in the middle between 1 and 0, or 1 and 0 at the same time"),
Flashcard(question: " Number of bits is ___ to the power of the number of qubits", answer: "2"),
Flashcard(question: " Quantum computing allows us to search through ___ amounts of data in a short period of time", answer: "Enormous"),
Flashcard(question: " Post-Quantum Cryptography", answer: "A new kind of cryptographic algorithm that can be implemented using today's classical computers but is also impervious to attacks from future quantum computers"),
Flashcard(question: " NTRU", answer: "Uses close vector problem to make even quantum computing difficult to calculate"),
Flashcard(question: " Quantum Key Distribution", answer: "Sends a random string of qubits (the key) across a quantum network channel"),
Flashcard(question: " In Quantum Key Distribution ___ verify that the key is identical", answer: "Both Sides"),
Flashcard(question: " Stream Cipher", answer: "Encrypts one byte at a time; high speed, low hardware complexity"),
Flashcard(question: " Stream ciphers are usually used with ___ encryption", answer: "Symmetric"),
Flashcard(question: " An ___ is often added to the stream cipher to add some randomization to the encryption process", answer: "Initialization Vector (IV)"),
Flashcard(question: " Block Cipher", answer: "Encrypts a fixed length block of information at a time"),
Flashcard(question: " Block cipher usually use ___ or ___ bit blocks", answer: "64 128"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ is often added to shorter blocks", answer: "Padding"),
Flashcard(question: " Block ciphers often use ___ encryption", answer: "Symmetric"),
Flashcard(question: " ECB (Electronic Code Book)", answer: "Simplest cipher mode, each block encrypted with same key, not recommended"),
Flashcard(question: " For ECB, the ___ and ___ are identical for every block", answer: "Input Output"),
Flashcard(question: " CBC (Cipher Block Chaining)", answer: "Performs a different set of input and output to data in each block"),
Flashcard(question: " XOR", answer: "Exclusive Or, two identical bits have a 0 output, two different bits have a 1 output"),
Flashcard(question: " Unlike ECB, CBC adds an ___ before the block cipher encryption", answer: "Initialization Vector"),
Flashcard(question: " For the second block in a CBC encryption, we use the ___ as the initialization vector for the next block", answer: "Previous Ciphertext"),
Flashcard(question: " CTR (Counter Mode)", answer: "Uses an incremental counter to be able to add randomization to the encryption process."),
Flashcard(question: " Incremental Counter", answer: "A loop that changes the value of a count by a certain amount every time an event occurs"),
Flashcard(question: " GCM (Galois Counter Mode)", answer: "A mode of operation used for encryption. It combines the Counter (CTM) mode with hashing techniques for data authenticity and confidentiality"),
Flashcard(question: " Blockchain", answer: "A distributed and decentralized ledger that records and verifies transactions and ownership, making it difficult to tamper with or shut down"),
Flashcard(question: " Blockchain verifies a ___ then adds it to a block of verified ones", answer: "Transaction"),
Flashcard(question: " A ___ is added to a new block of verified transactions in a blockchain; if modified, block is invalid", answer: "Hash"),
Flashcard(question: " It's common to use a ___ symmetric key for mobile or other small power devices", answer: "Smaller"),
Flashcard(question: " Cryptography needs a CPU with a high amount of___ and ___", answer: "Speed Power"),
Flashcard(question: " Encrypting ___ than the normal block size will fill storage space since the block has to be filled in", answer: "Less"),
Flashcard(question: " The weak IV in ___ resulted in WEP security issues", answer: "RC4"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ encryption is the slower of the two", answer: "Asymmetric"),
Flashcard(question: " ___ devices often have the key embedded in the firmware, not allowing you to change it", answer: "IoT"),
Flashcard(question: " Information Security", answer: "Act of protecting data and information from unauthorized access, unlawful modification and disruption, disclosure, corruption, and destruction"),
Flashcard(question: " Information Systems Security", answer: "Act of protecting the systems that hold and process our critical data"),
Flashcard(question: " Confidentiality", answer: "Information has not been disclosed to unauthorized people"),
Flashcard(question: " Integrity", answer: "Information has not been modified or altered without proper authorization"),
Flashcard(question: " Availability", answer: "Information is able to be stored, accessed, or protected at all times"),
Flashcard(question: " Authentication", answer: "When a person's identity is established with proof and confirmed by a system"),
Flashcard(question: " Authorization", answer: "Occurs when a user is given access to a certain piece of data or certain areas of a building"),
Flashcard(question: " Accounting", answer: "Tracking of data, computer usage, and network resources"),
Flashcard(question: " Malware", answer: "Short-hand term for malicious software"),
Flashcard(question: " Unauthorized Access", answer: "Occurs when access to computer resources and data happens without the consent of the owner"),
Flashcard(question: " System Failure", answer: "Occurs when a computer crashes or an individual application fails"),
Flashcard(question: " Social Engineering", answer: "Act of manipulating users into revealing confidential information or performing other detrimental actions"),
Flashcard(question: " Physical controls", answer: "Alarm systems, locks, surveillance cameras, identification cards, and security guards"),
Flashcard(question: " Technical controls", answer: "Smart cards, encryption, access control lists (ACLs), intrusion detection systems, and network authentication"),
Flashcard(question: " Administrative controls", answer: "Policies, procedures, security awareness training, contingency planning, and disaster recovery plans"),
Flashcard(question: " White Hats", answer: "Non-malicious hackers who attempt to break into a company's systems at their request"),
Flashcard(question: " Black Hats", answer: "Malicious hackers who break into computer systems and networks without authorization or permission"),
Flashcard(question: " Gray Hats", answer: "Hackers without any affiliation to a company who attempt to break into a company's network but risk the law by doing so"),
Flashcard(question: " Blue Hats", answer: "Hackers who attempt to hack into a network with permission of the company but are not employed by the company"),
Flashcard(question: " Elite", answer: "Hackers who find and exploit vulnerabilities before anyone else does"),
Flashcard(question: " Script Kiddie", answer: "Hackers with little to no skill who only use the tools and exploits written by others"),
Flashcard(question: " Hacktivists", answer: "Hackers who are driven by a cause like social change, political agendas, or terrorism"),
Flashcard(question: " Organized Crime", answer: "Hackers who are part of a crime group that is well-funded and highly sophisticated"),
Flashcard(question: " Advanced Persistent Threat (APT)", answer: "Highly trained and funded groups of hackers (often by nation states) with covert and open-source intelligence at their disposal"),
Flashcard(question: " Timeliness", answer: "Property of an intelligence source that ensures it is up to date"),
Flashcard(question: " Relevancy", answer: "Property of an intelligence source that ensures it matches the use cases intended for it"),
Flashcard(question: " Accuracy", answer: "Property of an intelligence source that ensures it produces effective results"),
Flashcard(question: " Confidence Levels", answer: "Property of an intelligence source that ensures it produces qualified statements about reliability"),
Flashcard(question: " propriety", answer: "Threat intelligence is very widely provided as a commercial service offering, where access to updates and research is subject to a subscription fee"),
Flashcard(question: " Closed-source", answer: "Data that is derived from the provider's own research and analysis efforts, such as data from honeynets that they operate, plus information mined from its customers' systems, suitably anonymized"),
Flashcard(question: " Open-source", answer: "Data that is available to use without subscription, which may include threat feeds similar to the commercial providers and may contain reputation lists and malware signature databases"),
Flashcard(question: " Open-Source Intelligence (OSINT)", answer: "Methods of obtaining information about a person or organization through public records, websites, and social media"),
Flashcard(question: " Threat Hunting", answer: "Cybersecurity technique designed to detect presence of threats that have not been discovered by normal security monitoring."),
Flashcard(question: " Establishing a hypothesis (Threat Hunting)", answer: "A hypothesis is derived from the threat modeling and is based on potential events with higher likelihood and higher impact."),
Flashcard(question: " Profiling Threat Actors and Activities (Threat Hunting)", answer: "Involves the creation of scenarios that show how a prospective attacker might attempt an intrusion and what their objectives might be"),
Flashcard(question: " Kill Chain", answer: "A model developed by Lockheed Martin that describes the stages by which a threat actor progresses a network intrusion."),
Flashcard(question: " Reconnaissance", answer: "The attacker determines what methods to use to complete the phases of the attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Weaponization", answer: "The attacker couples payload code that will enable access with exploit code that will use a vulnerability to execute on the target system"),
Flashcard(question: " Delivery", answer: "The attacker identifies a vector by which to transmit the weaponized code to the target environment"),
Flashcard(question: " Exploitation", answer: "The weaponized code is executed on the target system by this mechanism"),
Flashcard(question: " Installation", answer: "This mechanism enables the weaponized code to run a remote access tool and achieve persistence on the target system"),
Flashcard(question: " Command & Control (C2)", answer: "The weaponized code establishes an outbound channel to a remote server that can then be used to control the remote access tool and possibly download additional tools to progress the attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Actions on Objectives", answer: "The attacker typically uses the access he has achieved to covertly collect information from target systems and transfer it to a remote system (data exfiltration) or achieve other goals and motives"),
Flashcard(question: " MTRE ATT&CK Framework", answer: "A knowledge base maintained by the MITRE Corporation for listing and explaining specific adversary tactics, techniques, and common knowledge or procedures"),
Flashcard(question: " Diamond Model of Intrusion Analysis", answer: "A framework for analyzing cybersecurity incidents and intrusions by exploring the relationships between four core features: adversary, capability, infrastructure, and victim"),
Flashcard(question: " Virus", answer: "Malicious code that runs on a machine without the user's knowledge and infects the computer when executed"),
Flashcard(question: " Boot sector virus", answer: "viruses are stored in the first sector of a hard drive and are loaded into memory upon boot up"),
Flashcard(question: " Macro virus", answer: "virus embedded into a document and is executed when the document is opened by the user"),
Flashcard(question: " Program virus", answer: "infect an executable or application"),
Flashcard(question: " multipartite virus", answer: "Virus that combines boot and program viruses to first attach itself to the boot sector and system files before attacking other files on the computer"),
Flashcard(question: " Polymorphic virus", answer: "advanced version of an encrypted virus that changes itself every time it is executed by altering the decryption module to avoid detection"),
Flashcard(question: " Metamorphic virus", answer: "Virus that is able to rewrite itself entirely before it attempts to infect a file (advanced version of polymorphic virus)"),
Flashcard(question: " Armored virus", answer: "have a layer of protection to confuse a program or person analyzing it"),
Flashcard(question: " hoax virus", answer: "A type of virus that's not really a virus but simply an e-mail announcement of a made-up virus. Its harm lies in people believing the announcement and forwarding the e-mail on to others."),
Flashcard(question: " Worm", answer: "Malicious software, like a virus, but is able to replicate itself without user interaction"),
Flashcard(question: " Trojan Horse", answer: "Malicious software that is disguised as a piece of harmless or desirable software"),
Flashcard(question: " Remote Access Trojan (RAT)", answer: "Provides the attacker with remote control of a victim computer and is the most commonly used type of Trojan"),
Flashcard(question: " Ransomware", answer: "Malware that restricts access to a victim's computer system until a ransom is received"),
Flashcard(question: " Spyware", answer: "Malware that secretly gathers information about the user without their consent"),
Flashcard(question: " Grayware", answer: "Software that isn't benign nor malicious and tends to behave improperly without any serious consequences"),
Flashcard(question: " Rootkit", answer: "Software designed to gain administrative level control over a system without detection"),
Flashcard(question: " DLL injection", answer: "Malicious code is inserted into a running process on a Windows machine by taking advantage of Dynamic Link Libraries that are loaded at runtime"),
Flashcard(question: " Driver manipulation", answer: "An attack that relies on compromising the kernel-mode device drivers that operate at a privileged or system level"),
Flashcard(question: " Spam", answer: "Activity that abuses electronic messaging systems, most commonly through email"),
Flashcard(question: " Threat vector", answer: "Method used by an attacker to access a victim's machine"),
Flashcard(question: " attack vector", answer: "Method used by an attacker to gain access to a victim's machine in order to infect it with malware"),
Flashcard(question: " Watering Holes", answer: "Malware is placed on a website that you know your potential victims will access"),
Flashcard(question: " Botnet", answer: "A collection of compromised computers under the control of a master node"),
Flashcard(question: " Active Interception", answer: "Occurs when a computer is placed between the sender and receiver and is able to capture or modify the traffic between them"),
Flashcard(question: " Privilege Escalation", answer: "Occurs when you are able to exploit a design flaw or bug in a system to gain access to resources that a normal user isn't able to access"),
Flashcard(question: " Easter Egg", answer: "Non-malicious code that when invoked, displays an insider joke, hidden message, or secret feature"),
Flashcard(question: " Logic Bomb", answer: "Malicious code that has been inserted inside a program and will execute only when certain conditions have been met"),
Flashcard(question: " step 1 Malware removal", answer: "identify symptoms of a malware infection"),
Flashcard(question: " Step 2 Malware removal", answer: "Quarantine the infected systems"),
Flashcard(question: " step 3 malware removal", answer: "Disable System Restore (in Windows)"),
Flashcard(question: " step 4 malware removal", answer: "remediate the infected system"),
Flashcard(question: " step 5 malware removal", answer: "schedule automatic updates and scans"),
Flashcard(question: " step 6 malware removal", answer: "enable system restore and create a new restore point"),
Flashcard(question: " step 7 malware removal", answer: "provide end user security awareness training"),
Flashcard(question: " step 1 preventing malware", answer: "update your anti-malware software automatically and scan your computer"),
Flashcard(question: " step 2 preventing malware", answer: "update and patch the OS and applications regularly"),
Flashcard(question: " step 3 preventing malware", answer: "educate and train end users on safe internet surfing practices"),
Flashcard(question: " Exploit Technique", answer: "Describes the specific method by which malware code infects a target host"),
Flashcard(question: " Dropper", answer: "Malware designed to install other types of malware embedded in a payload on an infected host"),
Flashcard(question: " Downloader", answer: "A pieced of code that connects to the internet to retrieve additional tools after the initial infection by a dropper"),
Flashcard(question: " Shellcode", answer: "Any lightweight code designed to run an exploit on the target, which may include any type of code format from scripting languages to binary code"),
Flashcard(question: " Code injection", answer: "Exploit technique that runs malicious code with the identification number of a legitimate process"),
Flashcard(question: " Living Off the Land", answer: "Exploit techniques that use standard system tools and packages to perform intrusions"),
Flashcard(question: " Personal Firewalls/Host-base Firewalls", answer: "Software application that protects a single computer from unwanted internet traffic"),
Flashcard(question: " Intrusion Detection System (IDS)", answer: "Device or software application that monitors a system or network and analyzes the data passing through it in order to identify an incident or attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Signature-based", answer: "A specific string of bytes triggers an alert"),
Flashcard(question: " policy-based", answer: "Relies on specific declaration of the security policy (i.e., 'No Telnet Authorized')"),
Flashcard(question: " anomaly-based", answer: "Analyzes the current traffic against an established baseline and triggers an alert if outside the statistical average"),
Flashcard(question: " True positive", answer: "Malicious activity is identified as an attack"),
Flashcard(question: " True negative", answer: "Legitimate activity is identified as legitimate traffic"),
Flashcard(question: " False positive", answer: "Legitimate activity is identified as an attack"),
Flashcard(question: " False negative", answer: "Malicious activity is identified as legitimate traffic"),
Flashcard(question: " Content Filters", answer: "Blocking of external files containing JavaScript, images, or web pages from loading in a browser"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Loss Prevention (DLP)", answer: "Monitors the data of a system while in use, in transit, or at rest to detect attempts to steal the data"),
Flashcard(question: " endpoint dlp system", answer: "Software-based client that monitors the data in use on a computer and can stop a file transfer or alert an admin of the occurrence"),
Flashcard(question: " network dlp system", answer: "Software or hardware-based solution that is installed on the perimeter of the network to detect data in transit"),
Flashcard(question: " storage dlp system", answer: "Software installed on servers in the datacenter to inspect the data at rest"),
Flashcard(question: " cloud dlp system", answer: "Cloud software as a service that protects data being stored in cloud services"),
Flashcard(question: " Self-Encrypting Drive (SED)", answer: "Storage device that performs whole disk encryption by using embedded hardware"),
Flashcard(question: " FileVault", answer: "A feature of Mac OS X that will encrypt all the files in the Home folder."),
Flashcard(question: " BitLocker", answer: "a microsoft utility to encrypt a drive"),
Flashcard(question: " Trust Platform Module (TPM)", answer: "chip residing on the motherboard that contains an encryption key"),
Flashcard(question: " Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)", answer: "Symmetric key encryption that supports 128-bit and 256-bit keys"),
Flashcard(question: " Hardware Security Module (HSM)", answer: "Physical devices that act as a secure cryptoprocessor during the encryption process"),
Flashcard(question: " Anti-virus (AV)", answer: "Software capable of detecting and removing virus infections and (in most cases) other types of malware, such as worms, Trojans, rootkits, adware, spyware, password crackers, network mappers, DoS tools, and others"),
Flashcard(question: " Host-based IDS/IPS (HIDS/HIPS)", answer: "A type of IDS or IPS that monitors a computer system for unexpected behavior or drastic changes to the system's state on an endpoint"),
Flashcard(question: " Endpoint Protection Platform (EPP)", answer: "A software agent and monitoring system that performs multiple security tasks such as anti-virus, HIDS/HIPS, firewall, DLP, and file encryption"),
Flashcard(question: " Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR)", answer: "A software agent that collects system data and logs for analysis by a monitoring system to provide early detection of threats"),
Flashcard(question: " User and Entity Behavior Analytics (UEBA)", answer: "A system that can provide automated identification of suspicious activity by user accounts and computer hosts."),
Flashcard(question: " SIM", answer: "Integrated circuit that securely stores the international mobile subscriber identity (IMSI) number and its related key"),
Flashcard(question: " SIM Cloning", answer: "Allows two phones to utilize the same service and allows an attacker to gain access to the phone's data"),
Flashcard(question: " Bluejacking", answer: "sending unsolicited messages over bluetooth"),
Flashcard(question: " Bluesnarfing", answer: "Unauthorized access of information from a wireless device over a Bluetooth connection"),
Flashcard(question: " Remote Lock", answer: "Requires a PIN or password before someone can use the device"),
Flashcard(question: " Remote Wipe", answer: "Remotely erases the contents of the device to ensure the information is not recovered by the thief"),
Flashcard(question: " Mobile Device Management (MDM)", answer: "Centralized software solution that allows system administrators to create and enforce policies across its mobile devices"),
Flashcard(question: " Geotagging", answer: "Embedding of the geolocation into a piece of data (i.e photo)"),
Flashcard(question: " Storage Segmentation", answer: "Creating a clear separation between personal and company data on a single device"),
Flashcard(question: " step 1 mobile device hardening", answer: "update your device to the latest version of the software"),
Flashcard(question: " step 2 mobile device hardening", answer: "install antivirus"),
Flashcard(question: " step 3 mobile device hardening", answer: "train users on proper security and use of the device"),
Flashcard(question: " step 4 mobile device hardening", answer: "only install apps from the official mobile stores"),
Flashcard(question: " step 5 mobile device hardening", answer: "do not root or jailbreak your devices"),
Flashcard(question: " step 6 mobile device hardening", answer: "only use v2 SIM cards with your devices"),
Flashcard(question: " step 7 mobile device hardening", answer: "turn off all unnecessary features"),
Flashcard(question: " step 8 mobile device hardening", answer: "turn on encryption for voice and data"),
Flashcard(question: " step 9 mobile device hardening", answer: "use strong passwords or biometrics"),
Flashcard(question: " step 10 mobile device hardening", answer: "don't allow BYOD"),
Flashcard(question: " Hardening", answer: "Act of configuring an operating system securely by updating it, creating rules and policies to govern it, and removing unnecessary applications"),
Flashcard(question: " Least Functionality", answer: "Process of configuring workstation or server to only provide essential applications and services"),
Flashcard(question: " Application Allowlisting", answer: "Only applications that are on the list are allowed to be run by the operating system while all other applications are blocked"),
Flashcard(question: " Application Blocklisting", answer: "Any application placed on the list will prevented from running while all others will be permitted to run"),
Flashcard(question: " Trusted Operating System (TOS)", answer: "An operating system that meets the requirements set forth by government and has multilevel security"),
Flashcard(question: " Patches", answer: "A single problem-fixing piece of software for an operating system or application"),
Flashcard(question: " Security Update", answer: "Software code that is issued for a product-specific security-related vulnerability"),
Flashcard(question: " critical update", answer: "Software code for a specific problem addressing a critical, non-security bug in the software"),
Flashcard(question: " service pack", answer: "A tested, cumulative grouping of patches, hotfixes, security updates, critical updates, and possibly some feature or design changes"),
Flashcard(question: " windows update", answer: "Recommended update to fix a noncritical problem that users have found, as well as to provide additional features or capabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " driver update", answer: "Updated device driver to fix a security issue or add a feature to a supported piece of hardware"),
Flashcard(question: " patch management", answer: "Process of planning, testing, implementing, and auditing of software patches"),
Flashcard(question: " Group policy", answer: "A set of rules or policies that can be applied to a set of users or computer accounts within the operating system"),
Flashcard(question: " Baselining", answer: "Process of measuring changes in the network, hardware, and software environment"),
Flashcard(question: " NTFS", answer: "New Technology File System is the default file system format for Windows and is more secure because it supports logging, encryption, larger partition sizes, and larger file sizes than FAT32"),
Flashcard(question: " Due Diligence", answer: "A legal principle identifying a subject has used best practice or reasonable care when setting up, configuring, and maintaining a system"),
Flashcard(question: " Trusted Foundry", answer: "A microprocessor manufacturing utility that is part of a validated supply chain (one where hardware and software does not deviate from its documented function)"),
Flashcard(question: " Hardware Source Authenticity", answer: "The process of ensuring that hardware is procured tamper-free from trustworthy suppliers"),
Flashcard(question: " Hardware Root of Trust (ROT)", answer: "A cryptographic module embedded within a computer system that can endorse trusted execution and attest to boot settings and metrics"),
Flashcard(question: " Anti-tamper", answer: "Methods that make it difficult for an attacker to alter the authorized execution of software."),
Flashcard(question: " Unified Extensible Firmware Interface (UEFI)", answer: "A type of system firmware providing support for 64-bit CPU operation at boot, full GUI and mouse operation at boot, and better boot security."),
Flashcard(question: " Secure boot", answer: "A UEFI feature that prevents unwanted processes from executing during the boot operation."),
Flashcard(question: " Measured boot", answer: "A UEFI feature that gathers secure metrics to validate the boot process in an attestation report."),
Flashcard(question: " Attestation", answer: "A claim that the data presented in the report is valid by digitally signing it using the TPM's private key"),
Flashcard(question: " eFUSE", answer: "A means for software or firmware to permanently alter the state of a transistor on a computer chip"),
Flashcard(question: " trusted firmware updates", answer: "A firmware update that is digitally signed by the vendor and trusted by the system before installation"),
Flashcard(question: " secure processing", answer: "A mechanism for ensuring the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of software code and data as it is executed in volatile memory."),
Flashcard(question: " Processor Security Extensions", answer: "Low-level CPU changes and instructions that enable secure processing"),
Flashcard(question: " Trusted execution", answer: "The CPU's security extensions invoke a TPM and secure boot attestation to ensure that a trusted operating system is running"),
Flashcard(question: " Secure enclave", answer: "The extensions allow a trusted process to create an encrypted container for sensitive data"),
Flashcard(question: " Atomic Execution", answer: "Certain operations that should only be performed once or not at all, such as initializing a memory location"),
Flashcard(question: " bus encryption", answer: "Data is encrypted by an application prior to being placed on the data bus"),
Flashcard(question: " System virtual Machine", answer: "Complete platform designed to replace an entire physical computer and includes a full desktop/server operating system"),
Flashcard(question: " Processor virtual machine", answer: "Designed to only run a single process or application like a virtualized web browser or a simple web server"),
Flashcard(question: " Hypervisor", answer: "Manages the distribution of the physical resources of a host machine (server) to the virtual machines being run (guests)"),
Flashcard(question: " Application Containerization", answer: "A single operating system kernel is shared across multiple virtual machines but each virtual machine receives its own user space for programs and data"),
Flashcard(question: " VM Escape", answer: "An attack that allows an attacker to break out of a normally isolated VM by interacting directly with the hypervisor"),
Flashcard(question: " Data remnants", answer: "Contents of a virtual machine that exist as deleted files on a cloud-based server after deprovisioning of a virtual machine"),
Flashcard(question: " Privilege elevation", answer: "Occurs when a user is able to grant themselves the ability to run functions as a higher-level user"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtualization Sprawl", answer: "Occurs when virtual machines are created, used, and deployed without proper management or oversight by the system admins"),
Flashcard(question: " Cookies", answer: "Text files placed on a client's computer to store information about the user's browsing habits, credentials, and other data"),
Flashcard(question: " Locally Shared Object", answer: "Also known as Flash cookies, they are stored in your Windows user profile under the Flash folder inside of you AppData folder"),
Flashcard(question: " Add-ons", answer: "Smaller browser extensions and plugins that provide additional functionality to the browser"),
Flashcard(question: " Advanced Security Options", answer: "Browser configuration and settings for numerous options such as SSL/TLS settings, local storage/cache size, browsing history, and much more"),
Flashcard(question: " User Account Control", answer: "Prevents unauthorized access and avoids user error in the form of accidental changes"),
Flashcard(question: " Software Development Life Cycle", answer: "An organized process of developing a secure application throughout the life of the project"),
Flashcard(question: " SDLC Phase 1", answer: "Planning and Analysis"),
Flashcard(question: " SDLC Phase 2", answer: "Software/System Design"),
Flashcard(question: " SDLC Phase 3", answer: "implementation"),
Flashcard(question: " SDLC Phase 4", answer: "testing"),
Flashcard(question: " SDLC Phase 5", answer: "integration"),
Flashcard(question: " SDLC Phase 6", answer: "deployment"),
Flashcard(question: " SDLC Phase 7", answer: "maintenance"),
Flashcard(question: " Agile Development", answer: "Software development is performed in time-boxed or small increments to allow more adaptivity to change"),
Flashcard(question: " DevOps", answer: "Software development and information technology operations"),
Flashcard(question: " Defense in Depth", answer: "Layering of security controls is more effective and secure than relying on a single control"),
Flashcard(question: " Never Trust User Input", answer: "Any input that is received from a user should undergo input validation prior to allowing it to be utilized by an application"),
Flashcard(question: " Minimize Attack Surface", answer: "Reduce the amount of code used by a program, eliminate unneeded functionality, and require authentication prior to running additional plugins"),
Flashcard(question: " Create Secure Defaults", answer: "Default installations should include secure configurations instead of requiring an administrator or user to add in additional security"),
Flashcard(question: " Authenticity and Integrity", answer: "Applications should be deployed using code signing to ensure the program is not changed inadvertently or maliciously prior to delivery to an end user"),
Flashcard(question: " Fail Securely", answer: "Applications should be coded to properly conduct error handling for exceptions in order to fail securely instead of crashing"),
Flashcard(question: " Fix Security Issues", answer: "If a vulnerability is identified then it should be quickly and correctly patched to remove the vulnerability"),
Flashcard(question: " Rely on Trusted SDKs", answer: "SDKs must come from trusted source to ensure no malicious code is being added"),
Flashcard(question: " Black-box testing", answer: "Occurs when a tester is not provided with any information about the system or program prior to conducting the test"),
Flashcard(question: " White-box testing", answer: "Occurs when a tester is provided full details of a system including the source code, diagrams, and user credentials in order to conduct the test"),
Flashcard(question: " Gray-box testing", answer: "Security testing that is based on limited knowledge of an application's design."),
Flashcard(question: " Structured Exception Handling (SEH)", answer: "Provides control over what the application should do when faced with a runtime or syntax error"),
Flashcard(question: " Input Validation", answer: "Applications verify that information received from a user matches a specific format or range of values"),
Flashcard(question: " Static Analysis", answer: "Source code of an application is reviewed manually or with automatic tools without running the code"),
Flashcard(question: " Dynamic Analysis", answer: "Analysis and testing of a program occurs while it is being executed or run"),
Flashcard(question: " Fuzzing", answer: "Injection of randomized data into a software program in an attempt to find system failures, memory leaks, error handling issues, and improper input validation"),
Flashcard(question: " Backdoors", answer: "Code placed in computer programs to bypass normal authentication and other security mechanisms"),
Flashcard(question: " Directory Traversal", answer: "Method of accessing unauthorized directories by moving through the directory structure on a remote server"),
Flashcard(question: " arbitrary code execution", answer: "Occurs when an attacker is able to execute or run commands on a victim computer"),
Flashcard(question: " Remote Code Execution (RCE)", answer: "Occurs when an attacker is able to execute or run commands on a remote computer"),
Flashcard(question: " Zero Day", answer: "Attacks against a vulnerability that is unknown to the original developer or manufacturer"),
Flashcard(question: " Buffer Overflow", answer: "Occurs when a process stores data outside the memory range allocated by the developer"),
Flashcard(question: " Buffer", answer: "A temporary storage area that a program uses to store data"),
Flashcard(question: " Stack", answer: "Reserved area of memory where the program saves the return address when a function call instruction is received"),
Flashcard(question: " Smash the stack", answer: "Occurs when an attacker fills up the buffer with NOP so that the return address may hit a NOP and continue on until it finds the attacker's code to run"),
Flashcard(question: " Address Space Layout Randomization", answer: "Method used by programmers to randomly arrange the different address spaces used by a program or process to prevent buffer overflow exploits"),
Flashcard(question: " Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)", answer: "Occurs when an attacker embeds malicious scripting commands on a trusted website"),
Flashcard(question: " Stored/Persistent XSS", answer: "attempts to get data provided by the attacker to be saved on the web server by the victim"),
Flashcard(question: " Reflected XSS", answer: "Attempts to have a non-persistent effect activated by a victim clicking a link on the site"),
Flashcard(question: " Document Object Model DOM-based XSS", answer: "Attempt to exploit the victim's web browser"),
Flashcard(question: " cross-site request forgery (XSRF/CSRF)", answer: "Occurs when an attacker forces a user to execute actions on a web server for which they are already authenticated"),
Flashcard(question: " SQL Injection", answer: "Attack consisting of the insertion or injection of an SQL query via input data from the client to a web application"),
Flashcard(question: " Injection Attack", answer: "Insertion of additional information or code through data input from a client to an application"),
Flashcard(question: " XML Bomb (Billion Laughs Attack)", answer: "XML encodes entities that expand to exponential sizes, consuming memory on the host and potentially crashing it"),
Flashcard(question: " XML Eternal Entity (XXE)", answer: "An attack that embeds a request for a local resource"),
Flashcard(question: " Race Condition", answer: "A software vulnerability when the resulting outcome from execution processes is directly dependent on the order and timing of certain events, and those events fail to execute in the order and timing intended by the developer."),
Flashcard(question: " Dereferencing", answer: "A software vulnerability that occurs when the code attempts to remove the relationship between a pointer and the thing it points to"),
Flashcard(question: " Time of Check to Time of Use (TOCTTOU)", answer: "The potential vulnerability that occurs when there is a change between when an app checked a resource and when the app used the resource."),
Flashcard(question: " Insecure components", answer: "Any code that is used or invoked outside the main program development process"),
Flashcard(question: " Insufficient Logging and Monitoring", answer: "any program that does not properly record or log detailed enough information for an analyst to perform their job"),
Flashcard(question: " Weak or Default Configurations", answer: "Any program that uses ineffective credentials or configurations, or one in which the defaults have not been changed for security"),
Flashcard(question: " MAC Flooding", answer: "Attempt to overwhelm the limited switch memory set aside to store the MAC addresses for each port"),
Flashcard(question: " MAC Spoofing", answer: "Occurs when an attacker masks their own MAC address to pretend they have the MAC address of another device"),
Flashcard(question: " Access Control List (ACL)", answer: "An ordered set of rules that a router uses to decide whether to permit or deny traffic based upon given characteristics"),
Flashcard(question: " De-militarized Zone (DMZ)", answer: "Focused on providing controlled access to publicly available servers that are hosted within your organizational network"),
Flashcard(question: " Extranet", answer: "Specialized type of DMZ that is created for your partner organizations to access over a wide area network"),
Flashcard(question: " Internet-facing Host", answer: "Any host that accepts inbound connections from the internet"),
Flashcard(question: " Bastion Hosts", answer: "Hosts or servers in the DMZ which are not configured with any services that run on the local network"),
Flashcard(question: " Jumpbox", answer: "A hardened server that provides access to other hosts within the DMZ"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Access Control (NAC)", answer: "Security technique in which devices are scanned to determine its current state prior to being allowed access onto a given network"),
Flashcard(question: " Persistent Agents", answer: "A piece of software that is installed on the device requesting access to the network"),
Flashcard(question: " Non-persistent agents", answer: "Uses a piece of software that scans the device remotely or is installed and subsequently removed after the scan"),
Flashcard(question: " Switch Spoofing", answer: "Attacker configures their device to pretend it is a switch and uses it to negotiate a trunk link to break out of a VLAN"),
Flashcard(question: " Double Tagging", answer: "Attacker adds an additional VLAN tag to create an outer and inner tag"),
Flashcard(question: " Subnetting", answer: "Act of creating subnetworks logically through the manipulation of IP addresses"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Address Translation (NAT)", answer: "Process of changing an IP address while it transits across a router"),
Flashcard(question: " Port Address Translation (PAT)", answer: "Router keeps track of requests from internal hosts by assigning them random high number ports for each request"),
Flashcard(question: " Telephony", answer: "Term used to describe devices that provide voice communication to users"),
Flashcard(question: " Modem", answer: "A device that could modulate digital information into an analog signal for transmission over a standard dial-up phone line"),
Flashcard(question: " War Dialing", answer: "Dialing phone lines to find idle modems to use to enter a system, capture the attached computer, and gain access to its network(s)."),
Flashcard(question: " Perimeter Security", answer: "Security devices focused on the boundary between the LAN and the WAN in your organization's network"),
Flashcard(question: " packet-filtering firewall", answer: "Inspects each packet passing through the firewall and accepts or rejects it based on the rules"),
Flashcard(question: " stateless packet filtering", answer: "Inspects incoming packet and permits or denies based on conditions set by administrator"),
Flashcard(question: " stateful packet filtering", answer: "A firewall technology that keeps a record of the state of a connection between an internal computer and an external server and then makes decisions based on the connection as well as the rule base."),
Flashcard(question: " NAT Filtering", answer: "Filters traffic based upon the ports being utilized and type of connection (TCP or UDP)"),
Flashcard(question: " Application-layer gateway", answer: "conducts an in-depth inspection based upon the application being used"),
Flashcard(question: " circuit-level gateway", answer: "Operates at the session layer and only inspects the traffic during the establishment of the initial session over TCP or UDP"),
Flashcard(question: " Explicit allow", answer: "Traffic is allowed to enter or leave the network because there is an ACL rule that specifically allows it"),
Flashcard(question: " explicit deny", answer: "Traffic is denied the ability to enter or leave the network because there is an ACL rule that specifically denies it"),
Flashcard(question: " implicit deny", answer: "Traffic is denied the ability to enter or leave the network because there is no specific rule that allows it"),
Flashcard(question: " web application firewall", answer: "Firewall installed to protect your server by inspecting traffic being sent to a web application"),
Flashcard(question: " Proxy Server", answer: "A device that acts as a middle man between a device and a remote server"),
Flashcard(question: " IP Proxy", answer: "Secures a network by keeping machines behind it anonymous; it does this through the use of NAT."),
Flashcard(question: " Caching Proxy", answer: "Attempts to serve client requests by delivering content from itself without actually contacting the remote server"),
Flashcard(question: " Internet content filter", answer: "Used in organizations to prevent users from accessing prohibited websites and other content"),
Flashcard(question: " Web security gateway", answer: "A go-between device that scans for viruses, filters unwanted content, and performs data loss prevention functions"),
Flashcard(question: " Honeypot", answer: "A single computer (or file, group of files, or IP range) that might be attractive to an attacker"),
Flashcard(question: " Honeynet", answer: "A group of computers, servers, or networks used to attract an attacker"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Loss Prevention", answer: "Systems designed to protect data by conducting content inspection of data being sent out of the network"),
Flashcard(question: " network intrusion detection system (NIDS)", answer: "Attempts to detect, log, and alert on malicious network activities"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Intrusion Prevention System (NIPS)", answer: "Attempts to remove, detain, or redirect malicious traffic in a network. Can also perform functions as a protocol analyzer"),
Flashcard(question: " Unified Threat Management (UTM)", answer: "Combination of network security devices and technologies to provide more defense in depth within a single device"),
Flashcard(question: " Cloud Computing", answer: "A way of offering on-demand services that extend the traditional capabilities of a computer or network"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI)", answer: "VDI allows a cloud provider to offer a full desktop operating system to an end user from a centralized server"),
Flashcard(question: " Security as a Service (SECaaS)", answer: "Provides your organization with various types of security services without the need to maintain a cybersecurity staff"),
Flashcard(question: " File Servers", answer: "Servers are used to store, transfer, migrate, synchronize, and archive files for your organization"),
Flashcard(question: " FTP server", answer: "A specialized type of file server that is used to host files for distribution across the web"),
Flashcard(question: " Domain controller", answer: "A server that acts as a central repository of all the user accounts and their associated passwords for the network"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtual Private Cloud (VPC)", answer: "A private network segment made available to a single cloud consumer within a public cloud"),
Flashcard(question: " Cloud Access Security Broker (CASB)", answer: "Enterprise management software designed to mediate access to cloud services by users across all types of devices."),
Flashcard(question: " Forward Proxy", answer: "A security appliance or host positioned at the client network edge that forwards user traffic to the cloud network if the contents of that traffic comply with policy"),
Flashcard(question: " Reverse Proxy", answer: "An appliance positioned at the cloud network edge and directs traffic to cloud services if the contents of that traffic comply with policy"),
Flashcard(question: " Application Programming Interface (API)", answer: "A method that uses the brokers connections between the cloud service and the cloud consumer"),
Flashcard(question: " Function as a Service (FaaS)", answer: "A cloud service model that supports server-less software architecture by provisioning runtime containers in which code is executed in a particular programming language"),
Flashcard(question: " serverless", answer: "A software architecture that runs functions within virtualized runtime containers in a cloud rather than on dedicated server instances."),
Flashcard(question: " Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS)", answer: "A content delivery network policy that instructs the browser to treat requests from nominated domains as safe"),
Flashcard(question: " orchestration", answer: "The automation of multiple steps in a deployment process."),
Flashcard(question: " Continuous Integration (CI)", answer: "A software development method where code updates are tested and committed to a development or build server/code repository rapidly"),
Flashcard(question: " Continuous Delivery (CD)", answer: "a software development method where application and platform updates are committed to production rapidly"),
Flashcard(question: " Continuous deployment", answer: "A software development method where application and platform updates are committed to production rapidly"),
Flashcard(question: " DevSecOps", answer: "A combination of software development, security operations, and systems operations by integrating each discipline with the others"),
Flashcard(question: " infrastructure as Code (IaC)", answer: "A provisioning architecture in which deployment of resources is performed by scripted automation and orchestration."),
Flashcard(question: " snowflake systems", answer: "Any system that is different in its configuration compared to a standard template within an infrastructure as code architecture"),
Flashcard(question: " idempotence", answer: "A property of IaC that an automation or orchestration action always produces the same result, regardless of the component's previous state"),
Flashcard(question: " artificial intelligence (AI)", answer: "The science of creating machines with the ability to develop problem solving and analysis strategies without significant human direction or intervention."),
Flashcard(question: " Machine Learning (ML)", answer: "A component of AI that enables a machine to develop strategies for solving a task given a labeled dataset where features have been manually identified but without further explicit instructions"),
Flashcard(question: " Artificial Neural Network (ANN)", answer: "An architecture of input, hidden, and output layers that can perform algorithmic analysis of a dataset to achieve outcome objectives"),
Flashcard(question: " Deep Learning", answer: "A refinement of machine learning that enables a machine to develop strategies for solving a task given a labeled dataset and without further explicit instructions"),
Flashcard(question: " inbound port", answer: "A logical communication opening on a server that is listening for a connection from a client"),
Flashcard(question: " outbound port", answer: "A logical communication opening created on a client in order to call out to a server that is listening for a connection"),
Flashcard(question: " well known ports", answer: "Ports 0 to 1023 are considered well-known and are assigned by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA)"),
Flashcard(question: " registered ports", answer: "Ports 1024 to 49,151 are considered registered and are usually assigned to proprietary protocols"),
Flashcard(question: " Dynamic or private ports", answer: "Ports 49,152 to 65,535 can be used by any application without being registered with IANA"),
Flashcard(question: " Unnecessary Port", answer: "Any port that is associated with a service or function that is non-essential to the operation of your computer or network"),
Flashcard(question: " Denial of Service (DoS)", answer: "Term used to describe many different types of attacks which attempt to make a computer or server's resources unavailable"),
Flashcard(question: " Flood Attack", answer: "A specialized type of DoS which attempts to send more packets to a single server or host than they can handle"),
Flashcard(question: " Ping Flood", answer: "An attacker attempts to flood the server by sending too many ICMP echo request packets (which are known as pings)"),
Flashcard(question: " Smurf Attack", answer: "Attacker sends a ping to subnet broadcast address and devices reply to spoofed IP (victim server), using up bandwidth and processing"),
Flashcard(question: " Fraggle Attack", answer: "Attacker sends a UDP echo packet to port 7 (ECHO) and port 19 (CHARGEN) to flood a server with UDP packets"),
Flashcard(question: " SYN Flood", answer: "Variant on a Denial of Service (DOS) attack where attacker initiates multiple TCP sessions but never completes the 3-way handshake"),
Flashcard(question: " XMAS attack", answer: "A specialized network scan that sets the FIN, PSH, and URG flags set and can cause a device to crash or reboot"),
Flashcard(question: " Ping of Death", answer: "An attack that sends an oversized and malformed packet to another computer or server"),
Flashcard(question: " Teardrop attack", answer: "Attack that breaks apart packets into IP fragments, modifies them with overlapping and oversized payloads, and sends them to a victim machine"),
Flashcard(question: " Permanent Denial of Service", answer: "Attack which exploits a security flaw to permanently break a networking device by reflashing its firmware"),
Flashcard(question: " Fork bomb", answer: "Attack that creates a large number of processes to use up the available processing power of a computer"),
Flashcard(question: " Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS)", answer: "A group of compromised systems attack simultaneously a single target to create a Denial of Service (DOS)"),
Flashcard(question: " DNS amplification attack", answer: "Attack which relies on the large amount of DNS information that is sent in response to a spoofed query on behalf of the victimized server"),
Flashcard(question: " Blackholing or Sinkholing", answer: "Identifies any attacking IP addresses and routes all their traffic to a non-existent server through the null interface"),
Flashcard(question: " Spoofing", answer: "Occurs when an attacker masquerades as another person by falsifying their identity"),
Flashcard(question: " Hijacking", answer: "Exploitation of a computer session in an attempt to gain unauthorized access to data, services, or other resources on a computer or server"),
Flashcard(question: " Session Theft", answer: "Attacker guesses the session ID for a web session, enabling them to take over the already authorized session of the client"),
Flashcard(question: " TCP/IP hijacking", answer: "Occurs when an attacker takes over a TCP session between two computers without the need of a cookie or other host access"),
Flashcard(question: " Blind hijacking", answer: "Occurs when an attacker blindly injects data into the communication stream without being able to see if it is successful or not"),
Flashcard(question: " clickjacking", answer: "Attack that uses multiple transparent layers to trick a user into clicking on a button or link on a page when they were intending to click on the actual page"),
Flashcard(question: " man-in-the-middle (MITM) attack", answer: "Attack that causes data to flow through the attacker's computer where they can intercept or manipulate the data"),
Flashcard(question: " Man-in-the-browser (MITB) attack", answer: "occurs when a trojan infects a vulnerable web browser and modifies the web pages or transactions being done within the browser"),
Flashcard(question: " watering hole", answer: "Occurs when malware is placed on a website that the attacker knows his potential victims will access"),
Flashcard(question: " replay attack", answer: "Network-based attack where a valid data transmission is fraudulently or malicious rebroadcast, repeated, or delayed"),
Flashcard(question: " Null connection", answer: "A connection to the windows interprocess communication share (IPC)"),
Flashcard(question: " Block smb and NetBios", answer: "Use IPS at boundary"),
Flashcard(question: " DNS Poisoning", answer: "Occurs when the name resolution information is modified in the DNS server's cache"),
Flashcard(question: " Unauthorized Zone Transfer", answer: "Occurs when an attacker requests replication of the DNS information to their systems for use in planning future attacks"),
Flashcard(question: " Altered Hosts file", answer: "Occurs when an attacker modifies the host file to have the client bypass the DNS server and redirects them to an incorrect or malicious website"),
Flashcard(question: " Pharming", answer: "Occurs when an attacker redirects one website's traffic to another website that is bogus or malicious"),
Flashcard(question: " Domain Name Kiting", answer: "Attack that exploits a process in the way a domain name is registered so that the domain name is kept in limbo and cannot be registered by an authenticated buyer"),
Flashcard(question: " ARP", answer: "A protocol for mapping an Internet Protocol address (IP address) to a physical machine address that is recognized in the local network."),
Flashcard(question: " ARP poisoning", answer: "Attack that exploits the IP address to MAC resolution in a network to steal, modify, or redirect frames within the local area network"),
Flashcard(question: " Default accounts", answer: "A user or administrator-level account that is installed on a device by the manufacturer during production"),
Flashcard(question: " Weak passwords", answer: "A password should be long, strong, and complex. This should require at least 14 characters with a mix of uppercase, lowercase, numbers, and special characters"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Media", answer: "Copper, fiber optic, and coaxial cabling used as the connectivity method in a wired network"),
Flashcard(question: " Electromagnetic interference (EMI)", answer: "A disturbance that can affect electrical circuits, devices, and cables due to electromagnetic conduction and possibly radiation."),
Flashcard(question: " Radio Frequency Interference (RFI)", answer: "A disturbance that can affect electrical circuits, devices, and cables due to AM/FM transmissions or cell towers"),
Flashcard(question: " Crosstalk", answer: "Occurs when a signal transmitted on one copper wire creates an undesired effect on another wire"),
Flashcard(question: " Data Emanation", answer: "The electromagnetic field generated by a network cable or device when transmitting"),
Flashcard(question: " protected distribution system (PDS)", answer: "Secured system of cable management to ensure that the wired network remains free from eavesdropping, tapping, data emanations, and other threats"),
Flashcard(question: " Rogue Access Point", answer: "An unauthorized WAP or wireless router that allows access to the secure network"),
Flashcard(question: " Evil Twin", answer: "A rogue, counterfeit, and unauthorized WAP with the same SSID as your valid one"),
Flashcard(question: " Pre-Shared Key (PSK)", answer: "Same encryption key is used by the access point and the client"),
Flashcard(question: " Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP)", answer: "Original 802.11 wireless security standard that claims to be as secure as a wired network"),
Flashcard(question: " WiFi Protected Access (WPA)", answer: "Replacement for WEP which uses TKIP, Message Integrity Check (MIC), and RC4 encryption"),
Flashcard(question: " WiFi Protected Access version 2 (WPA2)", answer: "802.11i standard to provide better wireless security featuring AES with a 128-bit key, CCMP, and integrity checking"),
Flashcard(question: " WiFi Protected Setup (WPS)", answer: "Automated encryption setup for wireless networks at a push of a button, but is severely flawed and vulnerable"),
Flashcard(question: " Jamming", answer: "Intentional radio frequency interference targeting your wireless network to cause a denial of service condition"),
Flashcard(question: " AP isolation", answer: "Creates network segment for each client when it connects to prevent them from communicating with other clients on the network"),
Flashcard(question: " War Driving", answer: "Act of searching for wireless networks by driving around until you find them"),
Flashcard(question: " War Chalking", answer: "Act of physically drawing symbols in public places to denote the open, closed, and protected networks in range"),
Flashcard(question: " IV Attack", answer: "Occurs when an attacker observes the operation of a cipher being used with several different keys and finds a mathematical relationship between those keys to determine the clear text data"),
Flashcard(question: " WiFi Disassociation Attack", answer: "Attack that targets an individual client connected to a network, forces it offline by deauthenticating it, and then captures the handshake when it reconnects"),
Flashcard(question: " Brute Force Attack", answer: "Occurs when an attacker continually guesses a password until the correct one is found"),
Flashcard(question: " WPA3 - Enterprise Mode", answer: "Uses AES-256 encryption with a SHA-384 hash for integrity checking"),
Flashcard(question: " WPA3 - Personal mode", answer: "Uses CCMP-128 as the minimum encryption required for secure connectivity"),
Flashcard(question: " Simultaneous Authentication of Equals (SAE)", answer: "A secure password-based authentication and password-authenticated key agreement method"),
Flashcard(question: " Perfect Forward Secrecy or Forward Secrecy", answer: "A feature of key agreement protocols (like SAE) that provides assurance that session keys will not be compromised even if long-term secrets used in the session key exchange are compromised"),
Flashcard(question: " False Acceptance Rate (FAR)", answer: "Rate that a system authenticates a user as authorized or valid when they should not have been granted access to the system"),
Flashcard(question: " False Rejection Rate (FRR)", answer: "Rate that a system denies a user as authorized or valid when they should have been granted access to the system"),
Flashcard(question: " Crossover Error Rate (CER)", answer: "An equal error rate (ERR) where the false acceptance rate and false rejection rate are equal"),
Flashcard(question: " Fire suppression", answer: "Process of controlling and/or extinguishing fires to protect an organization's employees, data, equipment, and buildings"),
Flashcard(question: " class a fire", answer: "Common Combustibles such as paper, wood, furniture, clothing - Water, Foam"),
Flashcard(question: " class b fire", answer: "flammable and combustible liquids"),
Flashcard(question: " class c fire", answer: "electrical equipment"),
Flashcard(question: " class d fire", answer: "Combustible metals"),
Flashcard(question: " class k fire", answer: "cooking oils"),
Flashcard(question: " Wet Pipe Sprinkler System", answer: "Pipes are filled with water all the way to the sprinkler head and are just waiting for the bulb to be melted or broken"),
Flashcard(question: " Dry Pipe Sprinkler System", answer: "Pipes are filled with pressurized air and only push water into the pipes when needed to combat the fire"),
Flashcard(question: " pre-action sprinkler system", answer: "Similar to a dry pipe system, but there are requirements for it to be set off such as heat or smoke."),
Flashcard(question: " clean agent system", answer: "Fire suppression system that relies upon gas (HALON, FM-200, or CO2) instead of water to extinguish a fire"),
Flashcard(question: " Faraday cage", answer: "Shielding installed around an entire room that prevents electromagnetic energy and radio frequencies from entering or leaving the room"),
Flashcard(question: " TEMPEST", answer: "U.S. Government standards for the level of shielding required in a building to ensure emissions and interference cannot enter or exit the facility"),
Flashcard(question: " Controller Area Network (CAN)", answer: "A digital serial data communications network used within vehicles"),
Flashcard(question: " Internet of Things (IoT)", answer: "A group of objects (electronic or not) that are connected to the wider Internet by using embedded electronic components."),
Flashcard(question: " Embedded Systems", answer: "A computer system that is designed to perform a specific, dedicated function"),
Flashcard(question: " Programmable Logic Controller (PLC)", answer: "A type of computer designed for deployment in an industrial or outdoor setting that can automate and monitor mechanical systems."),
Flashcard(question: " System-on-chip (SoC)", answer: "A processor that integrates the platform functionality of multiple logical controllers onto a single chip."),
Flashcard(question: " real-time operating system (RTOS)", answer: "A type of OS that prioritizes deterministic execution of operations to ensure consistent response for time-critical tasks."),
Flashcard(question: " Field Programmable Gate Array (FPGA)", answer: "A processor that can be programmed to perform a specific function by a customer rather than at the time of manufacture."),
Flashcard(question: " Operation Technology (OT)", answer: "a communications network designed to implement an industrial control system rather than data networking"),
Flashcard(question: " Industrial Control Systems (ICS)", answer: "A network that manages embedded devices"),
Flashcard(question: " Fieldbus", answer: "Digital serial data communications used in operational technology networks to link PLCs"),
Flashcard(question: " Human Machine Interface (HMI)", answer: "Input and output controls on a PLC to allow a user to configure and monitor the system"),
Flashcard(question: " Data historian", answer: "Software that aggregates and catalogs data from multiple sources within an industrial control system"),
Flashcard(question: " Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition (SCADA)", answer: "A type of industrial control system that manages large-scale, multiple-site devices and equipment spread over geographically large areas."),
Flashcard(question: " Modbus", answer: "A communications protocol used in operational technology networks"),
Flashcard(question: " securing ICS step 1", answer: "establish administrative control over operational technology networks by recruiting staff with relevant expertise"),
Flashcard(question: " securing ICS step 2", answer: "implement the minimum network links by disabling unnecessary links, services, and protocols"),
Flashcard(question: " securing ICS step 3", answer: "develop and test a patch management program for OT networks"),
Flashcard(question: " securing ICS step 4", answer: "perform regular audits of logical and physical access to systems to detect possible vulnerabilities and intrusions"),
Flashcard(question: " Premise systems", answer: "Systems used for building automation and physical access security"),
Flashcard(question: " Physical Access Control Systems (PACS)", answer: "Components and protocols that facilitate the centralized configuration and monitoring of security mechanisms within offices and data centers"),
Flashcard(question: " Building Automation System (BAS)", answer: "Components and protocols that facilitate the centralized configuration and monitoring of mechanical and electrical systems within offices and data centers."),
Flashcard(question: " time-based one-time password (TOTP)", answer: "A password is computed from a shared secret and current time"),
Flashcard(question: " HMAC-based one-time password (HOTP)", answer: "A password is computed from a shared secret and is synchronized between the client and the server"),
Flashcard(question: " context-aware authentication", answer: "process to check the user's or system's attributes or characteristics prior to allowing it to connect"),
Flashcard(question: " single sign-on (SSO)", answer: "a default user profile for each user is created and linked with all of the resources needed"),
Flashcard(question: " federated identity management (FIdM)", answer: "A single identity is created for a user and shared with all of the organizations in a federation"),
Flashcard(question: " cross-certification", answer: "Utilizes a web of trust between organizations where each one certifies others in the federation"),
Flashcard(question: " trusted third-party", answer: "Organizations are able to place their trust in a single third-party (also called the bridge model)"),
Flashcard(question: " Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML)", answer: "Attestation model built upon XML used to share federated identity management information between systems"),
Flashcard(question: " OpenID", answer: "An open standard and decentralized protocol that is used to authenticate users in a federated identity management system"),
Flashcard(question: " 802.1x", answer: "Standardized framework used for port-based authentication on wired and wireless networks"),
Flashcard(question: " Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP)", answer: "A framework of protocols that allows for numerous methods of authentication including passwords, digital certificates, and public key infrastructure"),
Flashcard(question: " EAP-FAST", answer: "Provides flexible authentication via secure tunneling (FAST) by using a protected access credential instead of a certificate for mutual authentication"),
Flashcard(question: " Protected EAP (PEAP)", answer: "Supports mutual authentication by using server certificates and Microsoft's Active Directory to authenticate a client's password"),
Flashcard(question: " Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP)", answer: "A database used to centralize information about clients and objects on the network"),
Flashcard(question: " Kerberos", answer: "An authentication protocol used by Windows to provide for two-way (mutual) authentication using a system of tickets"),
Flashcard(question: " Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP)", answer: "Microsoft's proprietary protocol that allows administrators and users to remotely connect to another computer via a GUI"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtual Network Computing (VNC)", answer: "Cross-platform version of the Remote Desktop Protocol for remote user GUI access"),
Flashcard(question: " Password Authentication Protocol (PAP)", answer: "Used to provide authentication but is not considered secure since it transmits the login credentials unencrypted (in the clear)"),
Flashcard(question: " Challenge Handshake Authentication Protocol (CHAP)", answer: "Used to provide authentication by using the user's password to encrypt a challenge string of random numbers"),
Flashcard(question: " Virtual Private Network (VPN)", answer: "Allows end users to create a tunnel over an untrusted network and connect remotely and securely back into the enterprise network"),
Flashcard(question: " VPN concentrator", answer: "Specialized hardware device that allows for hundreds of simultaneous VPN connections for remote workers"),
Flashcard(question: " Split tunneling", answer: "A remote worker's machine diverts internal traffic over the VPN but external traffic over their own internet connection"),
Flashcard(question: " Remote Authentication Dial-In User Service (RADIUS)", answer: "provides centralized authentication of dial-up, VPN, and wireless authentication services for 802.1x and the extensible authentication protocol (EAP)"),
Flashcard(question: " RADIUS port", answer: "UDP 1812 & UDP 1813"),
Flashcard(question: " TACAS+ port", answer: "TCP 49"),
Flashcard(question: " Password Spraying", answer: "Brute force attack in which multiple user accounts are tested with a dictionary of common passwords."),
Flashcard(question: " credential stuffing", answer: "Brute force attack in which stolen user account names and passwords are tested against multiple websites."),
Flashcard(question: " broken authentication", answer: "A software vulnerability where the authentication mechanism allows an attacker to gain entry"),
Flashcard(question: " Access Control", answer: "Methods used to secure data and information by verifying a user has permissions to read, write, delete, or otherwise modify it"),
Flashcard(question: " Discretionary Access Control (DAC)", answer: "The access control policy is determined by the owner"),
Flashcard(question: " Mandatory Access Control (MAC)", answer: "An access control policy where the computer system determines the access control for an object"),
Flashcard(question: " Rule Based Access Control", answer: "Label-based access control that defines whether access should be granted or denied to objects by comparing the object label and the subject label"),
Flashcard(question: " Lattice-based access control (LBAC)", answer: "Utilizes complex mathematics to create sets of objects and subjects to define how they interact"),
Flashcard(question: " Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)", answer: "An access model that is controlled by the system (like MAC) but utilizes a set of permissions instead of a single data label to define the permission level"),
Flashcard(question: " Attribute-based access control (ABAC)", answer: "An access model that is dynamic and context-aware using IF-THEN statements"),
Flashcard(question: " Least privilege", answer: "Users are only given the lowest level of access needed to perform their job functions"),
Flashcard(question: " Separation of duties", answer: "Requires more than one person to conduct a sensitive task or operation"),
Flashcard(question: " Job rotation", answer: "occurs when users are cycled through various jobs to learn the overall operations better, reduce their boredom, enhance their skill level, and most importantly increase security"),
Flashcard(question: " Privilege Creep", answer: "Occurs when a user gets additional permission over time as they rotate through different positions or roles"),
Flashcard(question: " User Access Recertification", answer: "Process where each user's rights and permissions are revalidated to ensure they are correct"),
Flashcard(question: " Propagation", answer: "Occurs when permissions are passed to a subfolder from the parent through inheritance"),
Flashcard(question: " User Account Control (UAC)", answer: "A security component in Windows that keeps every user in standard user mode instead of acting like an administrative user"),
Flashcard(question: " Risk Assessments", answer: "A process used inside of risk management to identify how much risk exists in a given network or system"),
Flashcard(question: " Risk", answer: "The probability that a risk will be realized"),
Flashcard(question: " Risk Transfer", answer: "A strategy that passes the risk to a third party"),
Flashcard(question: " Risk mitigation", answer: "A strategy that seeks to minimize the risk to an acceptable level"),
Flashcard(question: " Risk acceptance", answer: "A strategy that seeks to accept the current level of risk and the costs associated with it if the risk were realized"),
Flashcard(question: " Residual risk", answer: "The risk remaining after trying to avoid, transfer, or mitigate the risk"),
Flashcard(question: " Qualitative Risk Analysis", answer: "uses intuition, experience, and other methods to assign a relative value to risk"),
Flashcard(question: " Quantitative Risk Analysis", answer: "uses numerical and monetary values to calculate risk"),
Flashcard(question: " magnitude of impact", answer: "An estimation of the amount of damage that a negative risk might achieve"),
Flashcard(question: " Single Loss Expectancy (SLE)", answer: "Cost associated with the realization of each individualized threat that occurs"),
Flashcard(question: " Annualized Rate of Occurrence (ARO)", answer: "Number of times per year that a threat is realized"),
Flashcard(question: " Annualized Loss Expectancy (ALE)", answer: "Expected cost of a realized threat over a given year"),
Flashcard(question: " Security Assessment", answer: "verify that the organization's security posture is designed and configured properly withstand attacks"),
Flashcard(question: " Active Assessment", answer: "Utilize more intrusive techniques, like scanning, hands-on testing, and probing of network data to determine vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " Passive Assessment", answer: "Utilize open source information, the passive collection and analysis of the network data, and other unobtrusive methods without making direct contact with the targeted systems"),
Flashcard(question: " Security controls", answer: "Methods implemented to mitigate a particular risk"),
Flashcard(question: " physical controls", answer: "Any security measures that are designed to deter or prevent unauthorized access to sensitive information or the systems that contain it"),
Flashcard(question: " technical controls", answer: "Safeguards and countermeasures used to avoid, detect, counteract, or minimize security risks to our systems and information"),
Flashcard(question: " administrative controls", answer: "Focused on changing the behavior of people instead of removing the actual risk involved"),
Flashcard(question: " management controls", answer: "Security controls that are focused on decision-making and the management of risk"),
Flashcard(question: " operational controls", answer: "Focused on the things done by people"),
Flashcard(question: " preventative controls", answer: "security controls that are installed before an event happens and are designed to prevent something from occurring"),
Flashcard(question: " detective controls", answer: "Used during the event to find out whether something bad might be happening"),
Flashcard(question: " corrective controls", answer: "Used after an event occurs"),
Flashcard(question: " compensating controls", answer: "used whenever you can't meet the requirement for a normal control"),
Flashcard(question: " external risk", answer: "Risks that are produced by a non-human source and are beyond human control"),
Flashcard(question: " internal risk", answer: "Risks that are formed within the organization, arise during normal operations, and are often forecastable"),
Flashcard(question: " legacy systems", answer: "An old method, technology, computer system, or application program which includes an outdated computer system still in use"),
Flashcard(question: " multiparty", answer: "A risk that refers to the connection of multiple systems or organizations with each bringing their own inherent risks"),
Flashcard(question: " IP theft", answer: "Risk associated with business assets and property being stolen from an organization in which economic damage, the loss of a competitive edge, or a slowdown in business growth occurs"),
Flashcard(question: " Software Compliance/Licensing", answer: "Risk associated with a company not being aware of what software or components are installed within its network"),
Flashcard(question: " Vulnerability assessment", answer: "Seeks to identify any issues in a network, application, database, or other systems prior to it being used that might compromise the system"),
Flashcard(question: " vulnerability management", answer: "Practice of finding and mitigating the vulnerabilities in computers and networks"),
Flashcard(question: " Tabletop Exercise (TTX)", answer: "Exercise that uses an incident scenario against a framework of controls or a red team"),
Flashcard(question: " Penetration test", answer: "A test that uses active tools and security utilities to evaluate security by simulating an attack on a system to verify that a threat exists, actively test it, bypass security controls, and then finally exploit vulnerabilities on a given system"),
Flashcard(question: " Red Team", answer: "The hostile or attacking team in a penetration test or incident response exercise."),
Flashcard(question: " Blue Team", answer: "The defensive team in a penetration test or incident response exercise."),
Flashcard(question: " White Team", answer: "Staff administering, evaluating, and supervising a penetration test or incident response exercise."),
Flashcard(question: " Open Vulnerability and Assessment Language (OVAL)", answer: "A standard designed to regulate the transfer of secure public information across networks and the Internet utilizing any security tools and services available"),
Flashcard(question: " OVAL Language", answer: "An XML schema used to define and describe the information being created by OVAL to be shared among the various programs and tools"),
Flashcard(question: " OVAL Interpreter", answer: "A reference developed to ensure the information passed around by these programs complies with the OVAL schemas and definitions used by the OVAL language"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Mapping", answer: "Discovery and documentation of physical and logical connectivity that exists in the network"),
Flashcard(question: " Banner grabbing", answer: "A technique used to gain information about servers and inventory the systems or services"),
Flashcard(question: " Network sniffing", answer: "The process of finding and investigating other computers on the network by analyzing the network traffic or capturing the packets being sent"),
Flashcard(question: " protocol analyzer", answer: "Software tool that allows for the capture, reassembly, and analysis of packets from the network"),
Flashcard(question: " Password analysis", answer: "a tool used to test the strength of your passwords to ensure your password policies are being followed"),
Flashcard(question: " password cracker", answer: "Uses comparative analysis to break passwords and systematically continues guessing until the password is determined"),
Flashcard(question: " password guessing", answer: "Occurs when a weak password is simply figured out by a person"),
Flashcard(question: " dictionary attack", answer: "Method where a program attempts to guess the password by using a list of possible passwords"),
Flashcard(question: " brute-force attack", answer: "Method where a program attempts to try every possible combination until it cracks the password"),
Flashcard(question: " cryptanalysis attack", answer: "Comparing a precomputed encrypted password to a value in a lookup table"),
Flashcard(question: " rainbow table", answer: "List of precomputed values used to more quickly break a password since values don't have to be calculated for each password being guessed"),
Flashcard(question: " rubber hose attack", answer: "Attempt to crack a password by threatening or causing a person physical harm in order to make them tell you the password"),
Flashcard(question: " signature-based", answer: "Network traffic is analyzed for predetermined attack patterns"),
Flashcard(question: " anomaly-based", answer: "A baseline is established and any network traffic that is outside of the baseline is evaluated"),
Flashcard(question: " Behavior-based", answer: "Activity is evaluated based on the previous behavior of applications, executables, and the operating system in comparison to the current activity of the system"),
Flashcard(question: " baselining", answer: "The process of measuring changes in networking, hardware, software, and so on."),
Flashcard(question: " baseline reporting", answer: "Documenting and reporting on the changes in a baseline"),
Flashcard(question: " security posture", answer: "The risk level to which a system, or other technology element, is exposed."),
Flashcard(question: " Promiscuous mode", answer: "Network adapter is able to capture all of the packets on the network, regardless of the destination MAC address of the frames carrying them"),
Flashcard(question: " non-promiscuous mode", answer: "Network adapter can only capture the packets directly addressed to itself"),
Flashcard(question: " port mirroring", answer: "One or more switch ports are configured to forward all of their packets to another port on the switch"),
Flashcard(question: " network tap", answer: "A physical device that allows you to intercept the traffic between two points on the network"),
Flashcard(question: " Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP)", answer: "A TCP/IP protocol that aids in monitoring network-attached devices and computers"),
Flashcard(question: " agents", answer: "Software that is loaded on a managed device to redirect information to the network management system"),
Flashcard(question: " Network Management System (NMS)", answer: "Software running on one or more servers to control the monitoring of network-attached devices and computers"),
Flashcard(question: " SNMPv3", answer: "Version of SNMP that provides integrity, authentication, and encryption of the messages being sent over the network"),
Flashcard(question: " Auditing", answer: "A technical assessment conducted on applications, systems, or networks"),
Flashcard(question: " 0", answer: "think of logs"),
Flashcard(question: " logs", answer: "Data files that contain the accounting and audit trail for actions performed by a user on a computer or network"),
Flashcard(question: " security logs", answer: "Logs the events such as successful and unsuccessful user logins to the system"),
Flashcard(question: " system logs", answer: "Logs the events such as a system shutdown and driver failures"),
Flashcard(question: " application logs", answer: "Logs the events for the operating system and third-party applications"),
Flashcard(question: " SYSLOG", answer: "A standardized format used for computer message logging that allows for the separation of the software that generates messages, the system that stores them, and the software that reports and analyzes them"),
Flashcard(question: " Log File Maintenance", answer: "Actions taken to ensure the proper creation and storage of a log file, such as the proper configuration, saving, back up, security, and encryption of the log files"),
Flashcard(question: " overwrite events", answer: "When a maximum log size is reached, the system can begin overwriting the oldest events in the log files to make room"),
Flashcard(question: " Write Once Read Many (WORM)", answer: "Technology like a DVD-R that allows data to be written only once but read unlimited times"),
Flashcard(question: " SIEM", answer: "A solution that provides real-time or near-real-time analysis of security alerts generated by network hardware and applications."),
Flashcard(question: " Splunk", answer: "A market-leading big data information gathering and analysis tool that can import machine-generated data via a connector or visibility add-on"),
Flashcard(question: " ELK/Elastic Stack", answer: "Collection of free and open-source SIEM tools that provides storage, search, and analysis functions"),
Flashcard(question: " ArcSight", answer: "A SIEM log management and analytics software that can be used for compliance reporting for legislation and regulations like HIPPA, SOX, and PCI DSS"),
Flashcard(question: " Alien Vault and OSSIM (Open-Source Security Information Management)", answer: "A SIEM solution originally developed by Alien Vault, now opened by AT&T, and rebranded as AT&T Cybersecurity"),
Flashcard(question: " QRadar", answer: "A SIEM log management, analytics, and compliance reporting platform created by IBM"),
Flashcard(question: " Graylog", answer: "An open-source SIEM with an enterprise version focused on compliance and supporting IT operations and DevOps"),
Flashcard(question: " Security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR)", answer: "a class of security tools that facilitates incident response, threat hunting, and security configuration by orchestrating automated runbooks and delivering data enrichment"),
Flashcard(question: " Next-gen SIEM", answer: "A security information and event monitoring system with an integrated SOAR"),
Flashcard(question: " Playbook", answer: "A checklist of actions to perform to detect and respond to a specific type of incident"),
Flashcard(question: " Runbook", answer: "An automated version of a playbook that leaves clearly defined interaction points for human analysis."),
Flashcard(question: " cryptography", answer: "The practice and study of writing and solving codes in order to hide the true meaning of information"),
Flashcard(question: " encryption", answer: "process of converting ordinary information (plaintext) into an unintelligible form (ciphertext)"),
Flashcard(question: " data at rest", answer: "Inactive data that is archived, such as data resident on a hard disk drive"),
Flashcard(question: " data in transit", answer: "Data crossing the network or data that resides in a computer's memory"),
Flashcard(question: " data in use", answer: "Data that is undergoing constant change"),
Flashcard(question: " Key", answer: "The essential piece of information that determines the output of a cipher."),
Flashcard(question: " Symmetric Algorithm (Private Key)", answer: "Encryption algorithm in which both the sender and the receiver must know the same secret using a privately-held key"),
Flashcard(question: " Symmetric Algorithms", answer: "DES, 3DES, IDEA, AES, Blowfish, Twofish, RC4, RC5, RC6"),
Flashcard(question: " asymmetric algorithm (Public Key)", answer: "Encryption algorithm where different keys are used to encrypt and decrypt the data"),
Flashcard(question: " Asymmetric Algorithms", answer: "Diffie-Hellman, RSA, and ECC"),
Flashcard(question: " Hybrid Implementation", answer: "Utilizes asymmetric encryption to securely transfer a private key that can then be used with symmetric encryption"),
Flashcard(question: " stream cipher", answer: "Utilizes a keystream generator to encrypt data bit by bit using a mathematical XOR function to create the ciphertext"),
Flashcard(question: " block cipher", answer: "Breaks the input into fixed-length blocks of data and performs the encryption on each block"),
Flashcard(question: " Digital Encryption Standard (DES)", answer: "encryption algorithm which breaks the input into 64-bit blocks and uses transposition and substitution to create ciphertext using an effective key strength of only 56-bits"),
Flashcard(question: " Triple DES (3DES)", answer: "Encryption algorithm which uses three separate symmetric keys to encrypt, decrypt, then encrypt the plaintext into ciphertext in order to increase the strength of DES"),
Flashcard(question: " International data encryption algorithm (IDEA)", answer: "Symmetric block cipher which uses 64-bit blocks to encrypt plaintext into ciphertext"),
Flashcard(question: " Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)", answer: "Symmetric block cipher that uses 128-bit, 192-bit, or 256-bit blocks and a matching encryption key size to encrypt plaintext into ciphertext"),
Flashcard(question: " blowfish", answer: "Symmetric block cipher that uses 64-bit blocks and a variable length encryption key to encrypt plaintext into ciphertext"),
Flashcard(question: " twofish", answer: "Symmetric block cipher that replaced blowfish and uses 128-bit blocks and a 128-bit, 192-bit, or 256-bit encryption key to encrypt plaintext into ciphertext"),
Flashcard(question: " Rivest Cipher 4 (RC4)", answer: "Symmetric stream cipher using a variable key size from 40-bits to 2048-bits that is used in SSL and WEP"),
Flashcard(question: " Rivest Cipher 5 (RC5)", answer: "Symmetric block cipher with a key size up to 2048-bits"),
Flashcard(question: " Rivest Cipher 6 (RC6)", answer: "Symmetric block cipher that was introduced as a replacement for DES but AES was chosen instead"),
Flashcard(question: " Digital Signature", answer: "A hash digest of a message encrypted with the sender's private key to let the recipient know the document was created and sent by the person claiming to have sent it"),
Flashcard(question: " Diffie-Hellman (DH)", answer: "Used to conduct key exchanges and secure key distribution over an unsecure network"),
Flashcard(question: " RSA", answer: "Asymmetric algorithm that relies on the mathematical difficulty of factoring large prime numbers"),
Flashcard(question: " Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC)", answer: "Algorithm that is based upon the algebraic structure of elliptic curves over finite fields to define the keys"),
Flashcard(question: " Pretty Good Privacy (PGP)", answer: "An encryption program used primarily for signing, encrypting, and decrypting e-mails in an attempt to increase the security of e-mail communications."),
Flashcard(question: " GNU Privacy Guard (GPG)", answer: "A newer and updated version of the PGP encryption suite that uses AES for its symmetric encryption functions"),
Flashcard(question: " Key management", answer: "Refers to how an organization will generate, exchange, store, and use encryption keys"),
Flashcard(question: " One-time pad", answer: "A stream cipher that encrypts plaintext information with a secret random key that is the same length as the plaintext input"),
Flashcard(question: " Pseudo-Random Number Generator (PRNG)", answer: "A simulated random number stream generated by a computer that is used in cryptography, video games, and more"),
Flashcard(question: " Steganography", answer: "the art and science of hiding information by embedding messages within other, seemingly harmless messages"),
Flashcard(question: " blockchain", answer: "A shared, immutable ledger for recording transactions, tracking assets and building trust"),
Flashcard(question: " Public ledger", answer: "A record-keeping system that maintains participants' identities in secure and anonymous form, their respective cryptocurrency balances, and a record book of all the genuine transactions executed between network participants"),
Flashcard(question: " Quantum Computing", answer: "A computer that uses quantum mechanics to generate and manipulate quantum bits (qubits) in order to access enormous processing powers"),
Flashcard(question: " what is a qubit?", answer: "A quantum bit composed of electrons or photons that can represent numerous combinations of 1s and 0s at the same time through superposition"),
Flashcard(question: " quantum communication", answer: "A communications network that relies on qubits made of photons (light) to send multiple combinations of 1s and 0s simultaneously which results in tamper resistant and extremely fast communications"),
Flashcard(question: " Post-quantum cryptography", answer: "A new kind of cryptographic algorithm that can be implemented using today's classical computers but is also impervious to attacks from future quantum computers"),
Flashcard(question: " ephemeral", answer: "a cryptographic key that is generated for each execution of a key establishment process"),
Flashcard(question: " Homomorphic Encryption", answer: "An encryption method that allows calculations to be performed on data without decrypting it first"),
Flashcard(question: " Hashing", answer: "A one-way cryptographic function which takes an input and produces a unique message digest"),
Flashcard(question: " Message Digest 5 (MD5)", answer: "Algorithm that creates a fixed-length 128-bit hash value unique to the input file"),
Flashcard(question: " Collision", answer: "Condition that occurs when two different files create the same hash digest"),
Flashcard(question: " Secure Hash Algorithm (SHA-1)", answer: "Algorithm that creates a fixed-length 160-bit hash value unique to the input file"),
Flashcard(question: " Secure Hash Algorithm (SHA-2)", answer: "Family of algorithms that includes SHA-224, SHA-256, SHA-348, and SHA-512"),
Flashcard(question: " Secure Hash Algorithm (SHA-3)", answer: "Family of algorithms that creates hash digests between 224-bits and 512-bits"),
Flashcard(question: " RACE Integrity Primitives Evaluation Message Digest (RIPEMD)", answer: "an open-source hash algorithm that creates a unique 160-bit, 256-bit, or 320-bit message digest for each input file"),
Flashcard(question: " Hash-based Message Authentication Code (HMAC)", answer: "Uses a hash algorithm to create a level of assurance as to the integrity and authenticity of a given message or file"),
Flashcard(question: " Code signing", answer: "Uses digital signatures to provide an assurance that the software code has not been modified after it was submitted by the developer"),
Flashcard(question: " LANMAN (LM Hash)", answer: "Original version of password hashing used by Windows that uses DES and is limited to 14 characters"),
Flashcard(question: " NT LAN Manager Hash (NTLM Hash)", answer: "Replacement for LM Hash that uses RC4 and was released with Windows NT 3.1 in 1993"),
Flashcard(question: " NTLMv2 Hash", answer: "Replacement for NTLM Hash that uses HMAC-MD5 and is considered difficult to crack. Used when you do not have a domain with Kerberos for"),
Flashcard(question: " Pass the hash", answer: "A technique that allows an attacker to authenticate to a remote server or service by using the underlying NTLM or LM hash instead of requiring the associated plaintext password"),
Flashcard(question: " Mimikatz", answer: "A penetration testing tool used to automate the harvesting of hashes and conducting the Pass the Hash attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Birthday attack", answer: "Technique used by an attacker to find two different messages that have the same identical hash digest"),
Flashcard(question: " Key stretching", answer: "A technique that is used to mitigate a weaker key by increasing the time needed to crack it"),
Flashcard(question: " salting", answer: "Adding random data into a one-way cryptographic hash to help protect against password cracking techniques"),
Flashcard(question: " Public Key Infrastructure (PKI)", answer: "An entire system of hardware, software, policies, procedures, and people that is based on asymmetric encryption"),
Flashcard(question: " Certificate", answer: "Digitally signed electronic document that binds a public key with a user identity."),
Flashcard(question: " X.509", answer: "Standard used PKI for digital certificates and contains the owner/user's information and the certificate authority's information"),
Flashcard(question: " Subject Alternative Name (SAN)", answer: "Allows a certificate owner to specify additional domains and IP addresses to be supported"),
Flashcard(question: " Basic Encoding Rules (BER)", answer: "The original ruleset governing the encoding of data structures for certificates where several different encoding types can be utilized"),
Flashcard(question: " Canonical Encoding Rules (CER)", answer: "a restricted version of the BER that only allows the use of only one encoding type"),
Flashcard(question: " Distinguished Encoding Rules (DER)", answer: "Restricted version of the BER which allows one encoding type and has more restrictive rules for length, character strings, and how elements of a digital certificate are stored in X.509"),
Flashcard(question: " Privacy-enhanced Electronic Mail (PEM)", answer: ".pem, .cer, .crt, or .key"),
Flashcard(question: " public key cryptographic system #12 (PKCS#12)", answer: ".p12"),
Flashcard(question: " Personal information exchange", answer: ".pfx"),
Flashcard(question: " public key cryptographic systems #7 (PKCS#7)", answer: ".p7b"),
Flashcard(question: " Registration Authority (RA)", answer: "Used to verify information about a user prior to requesting that a certificate authority issue the certificate"),
Flashcard(question: " Certificate Authority", answer: "The entity that issues certificates to a user"),
Flashcard(question: " Certificate Revocation List (CRL)", answer: "An online list of digital certificates that the certificate authority has revoked"),
Flashcard(question: " Online Certificate Status Protocol (OCSP)", answer: "A protocol that allows you to determine the revocation status of a digital certificate using its serial number"),
Flashcard(question: " OCSP Stapling", answer: "Allows the certificate holder to get the OCSP record from the server at regular intervals and include it as part of the SSL or TLS handshake"),
Flashcard(question: " Public Key Pinning", answer: "Allows an HTTPS website to resist impersonation attacks by presenting a set of trusted public keys to the user's web browser as part of the HTTP header"),
Flashcard(question: " Key Escrow", answer: "Occurs when a secure copy of a user's private key is held in case the user accidently loses their key"),
Flashcard(question: " Key Recovery Agent", answer: "A specialized type of software that allows the restoration of a lost or corrupted key to be performed"),
Flashcard(question: " Web of trust", answer: "A decentralized trust model that addresses issues associated with the public authentication of public keys within a CA-based PKI system"),
Flashcard(question: " Transitive trust", answer: "An indirect trust relationship created by two or more direct trust relationships."),
Flashcard(question: " Non-repudiation", answer: "The security principle of providing proof that a transaction occurred between identified parties. Repudiation occurs when one party in a transaction denies that the transaction took place."),
Flashcard(question: " Certificate Signing Request (CSR)", answer: "A user request for a digital certificate."),
Flashcard(question: " Secure Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions (S/MIME)", answer: "A standard that provides cryptographic security for electronic messaging"),
Flashcard(question: " Secure Socket Layer/Transport Layer Security", answer: "cryptographic protocols that provide secure internet communications for web browsing, instant messaging, email, VoIP, and many other services"),
Flashcard(question: " Downgrade attack", answer: "A protocol is tricked into using a lower quality version of itself instead of a higher quality version"),
Flashcard(question: " Layer 2 Tunneling Protocol (L2TP)", answer: "A connection between two or more computers or device that are not on the same private network"),
Flashcard(question: " IPSec", answer: "A TCP/IP protocol that authenticates and encrypts IP packets and effectively securing communications between computers and devices using this protocol"),
Flashcard(question: " Internet Key Exchange (IKE)", answer: "Method used by IPSec to create a secure tunnel by encrypting the connection between authenticated peers"),
Flashcard(question: " Authentication Header (AH)", answer: "Protocol used in IPSec that provides integrity and authentication"),
Flashcard(question: " Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP)", answer: "Provides integrity, confidentiality, and authenticity of packets by encapsulating and encrypting them"),
Flashcard(question: " Security Association (SA)", answer: "Establishment of secure connections and shared security information using certificates or cryptographic keys"),
Flashcard(question: " Transport Mode", answer: "Host-to-host transport mode only uses encryption of the payload of an IP packet but not its header"),
Flashcard(question: " Single point of failure", answer: "The individual elements, objects, or parts of a system that would cause the whole system to fail if they were to fail"),
Flashcard(question: " Redundant power supply", answer: "an enclosure that provides two or more complete power supplies"),
Flashcard(question: " Surge", answer: "An unexpected increase in the amount of voltage provided"),
Flashcard(question: " Spike", answer: "A short transient in voltage that can be due to a short circuit, tripped circuit breaker, power outage, or lightning strike."),
Flashcard(question: " Sag", answer: "An unexpected decrease in the amount of voltage provided."),
Flashcard(question: " Brownout", answer: "Occurs when the voltage drops low enough that it typically causes the lights to dim and can cause a computer to shut off"),
Flashcard(question: " Blackout", answer: "Occurs when there is a total loss of power for a prolonged period"),
Flashcard(question: " uninterruptible power supply (UPS)", answer: "Combines the functionality of a surge protector with that of a battery backup"),
Flashcard(question: " Backup generator", answer: "An emergency power system used when there is an outage of the regular electric grid power"),
Flashcard(question: " Redundant Array of Independent Disks (RAID)", answer: "Allows the combination of multiple physical hard disks into a single logical hard disk drive that is recognized by the operating system"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID 0", answer: "Provides data striping across multiple disks to increase performance"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID 1", answer: "Provides redundancy by mirroring the data identically on two hard disks"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID 5", answer: "Provides redundancy by striping data and parity data across the disk drives"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID 6", answer: "Provides redundancy by striping and double parity data across the disk drives"),
Flashcard(question: " RAID 10", answer: "Creates a striped RAID of two mirrored RAIDs (combines RAID 1 & RAID 0)"),
Flashcard(question: " Fault-resistant RAID", answer: "Protects against the loss of the array's data if a single disk fails (RAID 1 or RAID 5)"),
Flashcard(question: " Fault-tolerant RAID", answer: "Protects against the loss of the array's data if a single component fails (RAID 1, RAID 5, RAID 6)"),
Flashcard(question: " Disaster-tolerant RAID", answer: "Provides two independent zones with full access to the data (RAID 10)"),
Flashcard(question: " Cluster", answer: "Two or more servers working together to perform a particular job function"),
Flashcard(question: " Failover cluster", answer: "A secondary server can take over the function when the primary one fails"),
Flashcard(question: " Load-balancing cluster", answer: "Servers are clustered in order to share resources such as CPU, RAM, and hard disks"),
Flashcard(question: " Hot site", answer: "A near duplicate of the original site of the organization that can be up and running within minutes"),
Flashcard(question: " warm site", answer: "A site that has computers, phones, and servers but they might require some configuration before users can start working"),
Flashcard(question: " cold site", answer: "A site that has tables, chairs, bathrooms, and possibly some technical items like phones and network cabling"),
Flashcard(question: " Full backup", answer: "All of the contents of a drive are backed up"),
Flashcard(question: " incremental backup", answer: "Only conducts a backup of the contents of a drive that have changed since the last full or incremental backup"),
Flashcard(question: " differential backup", answer: "Only conducts a backup of the contents of a drive that has changed since the last full backup"),
Flashcard(question: " 10 Tape rotation", answer: "Each tape is used once per day for two weeks and then the entire set is reused"),
Flashcard(question: " Grandfather-Father-Son", answer: "Three sets of backup tapes are defined as the son (daily), the father (weekly), and the grandfather (monthly)"),
Flashcard(question: " towers of hanoi", answer: "Three sets of backup tapes (like the grandfather-father-son) that are rotated in a more complex system"),
Flashcard(question: " snapshot backup", answer: "Type of backup primarily used to capture the entire operating system image including all applications and data"),
Flashcard(question: " disaster recovery planning", answer: "The development of an organized and in-depth plan for problems that could affect the access of data or the organization's building"),
Flashcard(question: " Business Impact Analysis (BIA)", answer: "A systematic activity that identifies organizational risks and determines their effect on ongoing, mission critical operations."),
Flashcard(question: " Maximum Tolerable Downtime (MTD)", answer: "The longest period of time a business can be inoperable without causing irrevocable business failure."),
Flashcard(question: " Recovery Time Objective (RTO)", answer: "The length of time it takes after an event to resume normal business operations and activities."),
Flashcard(question: " Work Recovery Time (WRT)", answer: "The length of time in addition to the RTO of individual systems to perform reintegration and testing of a restored or upgraded system following an event"),
Flashcard(question: " Recovery Point Objective (RPO)", answer: "The longest period of time that an organization can tolerate lost data being unrecoverable."),
Flashcard(question: " Mean Time to Repair (MTTR)", answer: "Measures the average time it takes to repair a network device when it breaks"),
Flashcard(question: " Mean Time Between Failures (MTBF)", answer: "measures the average time between failures of a device"),
Flashcard(question: " insider threat", answer: "A person who works for or with your organization but has ulterior motives"),
Flashcard(question: " Phishing", answer: "an attempt to fraudulently obtain information from a user (usually by email)"),
Flashcard(question: " Spear Phishing", answer: "An attempt to fraudulently obtain information from a user, usually by email that targets a specific individual"),
Flashcard(question: " Whaling", answer: "A form of spear phishing that directly targets the CEO, CFO, CIO, CSO, or other high-value target in an organization"),
Flashcard(question: " Smishing", answer: "Phishing conducted over text messaging (SMS)"),
Flashcard(question: " Vishing", answer: "Phishing conducted over voice and phone calls"),
Flashcard(question: " Authority", answer: "People are more willing to comply with a request when they think it is coming from someone in authority"),
Flashcard(question: " Urgency", answer: "People are usually in a rush these days and urgency takes an advantage of that"),
Flashcard(question: " Social proof", answer: "People are more likely to click on a link through social media or based on seeing others have already clicked on it"),
Flashcard(question: " Scarcity", answer: "technique that relies on the fear of missing out on a good deal that is only offered in limited quantities or a limited time"),
Flashcard(question: " Likeability", answer: "A technique where the social engineer attempts to find common ground and shared interests with their target"),
Flashcard(question: " Fear", answer: "The use of threats or demands to intimidate someone into helping you in the attack"),
Flashcard(question: " Diversion theft", answer: "When a thief attempts to take responsibility for a shipment by diverting the delivery to a nearby location."),
Flashcard(question: " hoax", answer: "attempt at deceiving people people into believing something is false when it is true or vice versa"),
Flashcard(question: " shoulder surfing", answer: "When a person uses direct observation to find out a target's password, PIN, or other such authentication information."),
Flashcard(question: " eavesdropping", answer: "When a person uses direct observation to listen in to a conversation."),
Flashcard(question: " dumpster diving", answer: "When a person scavenges for private information in garbage containers"),
Flashcard(question: " baiting", answer: "When a malicious individual leaves malware-infected removable media, such as a USB drive or optical disc, lying around in plain view."),
Flashcard(question: " piggybacking", answer: "When an unauthorized person tags along with an authorized person to gain entry to a restricted area."),
Flashcard(question: " watering hole attack", answer: "When an attacker figures out where users like to go, and places malware to gain access to your organization"),
Flashcard(question: " Fraud", answer: "wrongful or criminal deception intended to result in financial or personal gain"),
Flashcard(question: " identity fraud", answer: "The use by one person of another person's personal information, without authorization, to commit a crime or to deceive or defraud that other person or a third person"),
Flashcard(question: " scam", answer: "a fraudulent or deceptive act or operation"),
Flashcard(question: " invoice scam", answer: "A scam in which a person is tricked into paying for a fake invoice for a service or product that they did not order"),
Flashcard(question: " Prepending", answer: "A technical method used in social engineering to trick users into entering their username and passwords by adding an invisible string before the weblink they click"),
Flashcard(question: " influence operations", answer: "The collection of tactical information about an adversary as well as the dissemination of propaganda in pursuit of a competitive advantage over an opponent"),
Flashcard(question: " hybrid warfare", answer: "A military strategy which employs political warfare and blends conventional warfare, irregular warfare and cyberwarfare with other influencing methods, such as fake news, diplomacy, and foreign electoral intervention"),
Flashcard(question: " clean desk policy", answer: "Policy where all employees must put away everything from their desk at the end of the day into locked drawers and cabinets"),
Flashcard(question: " data classification", answer: "Category based on the value to the organization and the sensitivity of the information if it were to be disclosed"),
Flashcard(question: " sensitive data", answer: "Any information that can result in a loss of security, or loss of advantage to a company, if accessed by unauthorized persons"),
Flashcard(question: " Public data", answer: "Has no impact to the company if released and is often posted in the open-source environment"),
Flashcard(question: " private data", answer: "Contains data that should only be used within the organization"),
Flashcard(question: " confidential data", answer: "Highest classification level that contains items such as trade secrets, intellectual property data, source code, and other types that would seriously affect the business if disclosed"),
Flashcard(question: " Sensitive but unclassified", answer: "Items that wouldn't hurt national security if released but could impact those whose data is contained in it"),
Flashcard(question: " secret data", answer: "Data that could seriously damage national security if disclosed"),
Flashcard(question: " top secret data", answer: "Data that could gravely damage national security if it were known to those who are not authorized for this level of information"),
Flashcard(question: " data ownership", answer: "The process of identifying the person responsible for the confidentiality, integrity, availability, and privacy of information assets."),
Flashcard(question: " Data owner", answer: "A senior (executive) role with ultimate responsibility for maintaining the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of an information asset."),
Flashcard(question: " data steward", answer: "A role focused on the quality of the data and associated metadata"),
Flashcard(question: " data custodian", answer: "A role responsible for handling the management of the system on which the data assets are stored"),
Flashcard(question: " privacy officer", answer: "A role responsible for the oversight of any PII/SPI/PHI assets managed by the company"),
Flashcard(question: " Personal Identifiable Information (PII)", answer: "A piece of data that can be used either by itself or in combination with some other pieces of data to identify a single person"),
Flashcard(question: " Privacy Act of 1974", answer: "Affects U.S. government computer systems that collects, stores, uses, or disseminates personally identifiable information"),
Flashcard(question: " Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA)", answer: "affects healthcare providers, facilities, insurance companies, and medical data clearing houses"),
Flashcard(question: " Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX)", answer: "Affects publicly-traded U.S. corporations and requires certain accounting methods and financial reporting requirements"),
Flashcard(question: " Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA)", answer: "Affects banks, mortgage companies, loan offices, insurance companies, investment companies, and credit card providers"),
Flashcard(question: " Federal Information Security Management (FISMA) Act of 2002", answer: "requires each agency to develop, document, and implement an agency-wide information systems security program to protect their data"),
Flashcard(question: " Help America Vote Act of 2002", answer: "Provides regulations that govern the security, confidentiality, and integrity of the personal information collected, stored, or processed during the election and voting process"),
Flashcard(question: " privacy", answer: "a data governance requirement that arises when collecting and processing personal data to ensure the rights of the subject's data"),
Flashcard(question: " General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)", answer: "Personal data cannot be collected processed or retained without the Individual's Informed consent"),
Flashcard(question: " Deidentification", answer: "Methods and technologies that remove identifying information from data before it is distributed"),
Flashcard(question: " data masking", answer: "A deidentification method where generic or placeholder labels are substituted for real data while preserving the structure or format of the original data."),
Flashcard(question: " tokenization", answer: "A deidentification method where a unique token is substituted for real data."),
Flashcard(question: " aggregation/banding", answer: "A deidentification technique where data is generalized to protect the individuals involved"),
Flashcard(question: " reidentification", answer: "An attack that combines a deidentification dataset with other data source to discover how secure the deidentification method used is"),
Flashcard(question: " Acceptable Use Policy (AUP)", answer: "Defines the rules that restrict how a computer, network, or other systems may be used"),
Flashcard(question: " change management policy", answer: "Defines the structured way of changing the state of a computer system, network, or IT procedure"),
Flashcard(question: " due diligence", answer: "Ensuring that IT infrastructure risks are known and managed."),
Flashcard(question: " due care", answer: "Mitigation actions that an organization takes to defend against the risks that have been uncovered during due diligence"),
Flashcard(question: " due process", answer: "a legal term that refers to how an organization must respect and safeguard a personnel's rights"),
Flashcard(question: " Security awareness training", answer: "Used to reinforce to users the importance of their help in securing the organization's valuable resources"),
Flashcard(question: " security training", answer: "Used to teach the organization's personnel the skills they need to perform their job in a more secure manner"),
Flashcard(question: " security education", answer: "generalized training (like Security+)"),
Flashcard(question: " Interconnection Security Agreement (ISA)", answer: "An agreement between parties intended to minimize security risks for data transmitted across a network."),
Flashcard(question: " business partnership agreement (BPA)", answer: "Conducted between two business partners that establishes the conditions of their relationship"),
Flashcard(question: " asset disposal", answer: "Occurs whenever a system is no longer needed"),
Flashcard(question: " degaussing", answer: "Exposes the hard drive to a powerful magnetic field which in turn causes previously-written data to be wiped from the drive"),
Flashcard(question: " 0", answer: "(unusable)"),
Flashcard(question: " Purging (Sanitizing)", answer: "Act of removing data in such a way that it cannot be reconstructed using any known forensic techniques"),
Flashcard(question: " clearing", answer: "Removal of data with a certain amount of assurance that it cannot be reconstructed"),
Flashcard(question: " Control Objectives for Information and Related Technology (COBIT)", answer: "a security framework that divides IT into four domains: plan and organize,  acquire and implement, deliver and support, monitor and evaluate"),
Flashcard(question: " Center for Internet Security (CIS)", answer: "Consensus-developed secure configuration guidelines for hardening (benchmarks) and prescriptive, prioritized, and simplified sets of cybersecurity best practices (configuration guides)"),
Flashcard(question: " risk management framework (RMF)", answer: "A process that integrates security and risk management activities into the system development life cycle through an approach to security control selection and specification that considers effectiveness, efficiency, and constraints due to applicable laws, directives, Executive Orders, policies, standards, or regulations"),
Flashcard(question: " Cybersecurity Framework (CSF)", answer: "A set of industry standards and best practices created by NIST to help organizations manage cybersecurity risks"),
Flashcard(question: " ISO 27001", answer: "An international standard that details requirements for establishing, implementing, maintaining and continually improving an information security management system (ISMS)"),
Flashcard(question: " ISO 27002", answer: "An international standard that provides best practice recommendations on information security controls for use by those responsible for initiating, implementing, or maintaining information security management systems (ISMS)"),
Flashcard(question: " ISO 27701", answer: "An international standard that acts as a privacy extension to the ISO 27001 to enhance the existing Information Security Management System (ISMS) with additional requirements in order to establish, implement, maintain, and continually improve a Privacy Information Management System (PIMS)"),
Flashcard(question: " ISO 31000", answer: "An international standard for enterprise risk management that provides a universally recognized paradigm for practitioners and companies employing risk management processes to replace the myriad of existing standards, methodologies, and paradigms that differed between industries, subject matters, and regions"),
Flashcard(question: " System and Organization Controls (SOC)", answer: "A suite of reports produced during an audit which is used by service organizations to issue validated reports of internal controls over those information systems to the users of those services"),
Flashcard(question: " cloud security alliance's cloud control matrix", answer: "Designed to provide fundamental security principles to guide cloud vendors and to assist prospective cloud customers in assessing the overall security risk of a cloud provider"),
Flashcard(question: " cloud security alliance's reference architecture", answer: "A methodology and a set of tools that enable security architects, enterprise architects, and risk management professionals to leverage a common set of solutions that fulfill their common needs to be able to assess where their internal IT and their cloud providers are in terms of security capabilities and to plan a roadmap to meet the security needs of their business"),
Flashcard(question: " incident response", answer: "A set of procedures that an investigator follows when examining a computer security incident."),
Flashcard(question: " incident management program", answer: "Program consisting of the monitoring and detection of security events on a computer network and the execution of proper responses to those security events"),
Flashcard(question: " 1st step incident management", answer: "preparation"),
Flashcard(question: " 2nd step incident management", answer: "identification"),
Flashcard(question: " 3rd step incident management", answer: "containment"),
Flashcard(question: " 4th step incident management", answer: "eradication"),
Flashcard(question: " 5th step incident management", answer: "recovery"),
Flashcard(question: " 6th step incident management", answer: "lessons learned"),
Flashcard(question: " Out-of-band communication", answer: "Signals that are sent between two parties or two devices that are sent via a path or method different from that of the primary communication between the two parties or devices"),
Flashcard(question: " senior leadership", answer: "Executives and managers who are responsible for business operations and functional areas"),
Flashcard(question: " legal", answer: "the business or organization's legal counsel is responsible for mitigating risk from civil lawsuits"),
Flashcard(question: " human resources (HR)", answer: "Used to ensure no breaches of the employment law or employee contract is made during an incident response"),
Flashcard(question: " public relations (PR)", answer: "Used to manage negative publicity from a serious incident"),
Flashcard(question: " regulatory bodies", answer: "Governmental organizations that oversee the compliance with specific regulations and law"),
Flashcard(question: " syslog / rsyslog / syslog-ng", answer: "Three variations of syslog which all permit the logging of data from different types of systems in a central repository"),
Flashcard(question: " journalctl", answer: "A Linux command line utility used for querying and displaying logs from journald, the systemd logging service on Linux"),
Flashcard(question: " nxlog", answer: "A multi-platform log management tool that helps to easily identify security risks, policy breaches or analyze operational problems in server logs, operation system logs and application logs"),
Flashcard(question: " netflow", answer: "A network protocol system created by Cisco that collects active IP network traffic as it flows in or out of an interface, including its point of origin, destination, volume and paths on the network"),
Flashcard(question: " sflow", answer: "Short for sampled flow, it provides a means for exporting truncated packets, together with interface counters for the purpose of network monitoring"),
Flashcard(question: " internet protocol flow information export (IPfix)", answer: "A universal standard of export for Internet Protocol flow information from routers, probes and other devices that are used by mediation systems, accounting/billing systems and network management systems to facilitate services such as measurement, accounting and billing by defining how IP flow information is to be formatted and transferred from an exporter to a collector"),
Flashcard(question: " metadata", answer: "data that describes other data by providing an underlying definition or description by summarizing basic information about data that makes finding and working with particular instances of data easier"),
Flashcard(question: " legal hold", answer: "A process designed to preserve all relevant information when litigation is reasonably expected to occur."),
Flashcard(question: " tracert/traceroute", answer: "A network diagnostic command for displaying possible routes and measuring transit delays of packets across an Internet Protocol network"),
Flashcard(question: " nslookup/dig", answer: "Utility used to determine the IP address associated with a domain name, obtain the mail server settings for a domain, and other DNS information"),
Flashcard(question: " ipconfig/ifconfig", answer: "Utility that displays all the network configurations of the currently connected network devices and can modify the DHCP and DNS settings"),
Flashcard(question: " nmap", answer: "An open-source network scanner that is used to discover hosts and services on a computer network by sending packets and analyzing their responses"),
Flashcard(question: " ping/pathping", answer: "Utility used to determine if a host is reachable on an Internet Protocol network"),
Flashcard(question: " hping", answer: "An open-source packet generator and analyzer for the TCP/IP protocol that is used for security auditing and testing of firewalls and networks"),
Flashcard(question: " netcat", answer: "Utility for reading from and writing to network connections using TCP or UDP which is a dependable back-end that can be used directly or easily driven by other programs and scripts"),
Flashcard(question: " arp", answer: "Utility for viewing and modifying the local Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) cache on a given host or server"),
Flashcard(question: " route", answer: "Utility that is used to view and manipulate the IP routing table on a host or server"),
Flashcard(question: " curl", answer: "A command line tool to transfer data to or from a server, using any of the supported protocols (HTTP, FTP, IMAP, POP3, SCP, SFTP, SMTP, TFTP, TELNET, LDAP or FILE)"),
Flashcard(question: " the harvester", answer: "A python script that is used to gather emails, subdomains, hosts, employee names, open ports and banners from different public sources like search engines, PGP key servers and SHODAN database"),
Flashcard(question: " scanless", answer: "Utility that is used to create an exploitation website that can perform Open port scans in a more stealth-like manner"),
Flashcard(question: " nessus", answer: "A proprietary vulnerability scanner that can remotely scan a computer or network for vulnerabilities"),
Flashcard(question: " dnsenum", answer: "Utility that is used for DNS enumeration to locate all DNS servers and DNS entries for a given organization"),
Flashcard(question: " sn1per", answer: "An automated scanner that can be used during a penetration test to enumerate and scan for vulnerabilities across a network"),
Flashcard(question: " cuckoo", answer: "An open source software for automating analysis of suspicious files"),
Flashcard(question: " head", answer: "a command-line utility for outputting the first ten lines of a file provided to it"),
Flashcard(question: " tail", answer: "A command-line utility for outputting the last ten lines of a file provided to it"),
Flashcard(question: " cat (concatenate)", answer: "A command-line utility for outputting the contents of a file to the screen"),
Flashcard(question: " grep", answer: "A command-line utility for searching plain-text data sets for lines that match a regular expression or pattern"),
Flashcard(question: " chmod", answer: "A command-line utility used to change the access permissions of file system objects"),
Flashcard(question: " logger", answer: "Utility that provides an easy way to add messages to the /var/log/syslog file from the command line or from other files"),
Flashcard(question: " PowerShell", answer: "A task automation and configuration management framework from Microsoft, consisting of a command-line shell and the associated scripting language"),
Flashcard(question: " Phishing", answer: "fraudulent attempt to obtain sensitive information or data, by disguising oneself as a trustworthy entity in an electronic communication."),
Flashcard(question: " Smishing", answer: "When someone tries to trick you into giving them your private information via a text or SMS message."),
Flashcard(question: " Vishing", answer: "Using social engineering over the telephone system to gain access to private personal and financial information for the purpose of financial reward"),
Flashcard(question: " Spam", answer: "irrelevant or unsolicited messages sent to a large number of Internet users, for illegitimate advertising, and other activities such as phishing, and spreading malware"),
Flashcard(question: " SPIM", answer: "Spam delivered through instant messaging (IM) instead of through e-mail messaging"),
Flashcard(question: " Spear Phishing", answer: "the act of sending emails to specific and well-researched targets while pretending to be a trusted sender"),
Flashcard(question: " Dumpster Diving", answer: "exploration of a system's trash bin for the purpose of finding details in order for a hacker to have a successful online assault."),
Flashcard(question: " Shoulder Surfing", answer: "When someone watches over your shoulder to nab valuable information as you key it into an electronic device."),
Flashcard(question: " Pharming", answer: "cyberattack intended to redirect a website's traffic to another, fake site."),
Flashcard(question: " Tailgating", answer: "Social engineering attempt by cyber threat actors in which they trick employees into helping them gain unauthorized access into the company premises."),
Flashcard(question: " Eliciting Information", answer: "Procedures or techniques involving interacting with and communicating with others that is designed to gather knowledge or inform"),
Flashcard(question: " Whaling", answer: "Spear phishing that focuses on one specific high level executive or influencer"),
Flashcard(question: " Prepending", answer: "Prepend is a word that means to attach content as a prefix. For example, a prepend command could be used in a scripting language that a programmer would enter into a certain function or code module. It would add certain characters of text to the beginning of some variable or object."),
Flashcard(question: " Identity Fraud", answer: "identity fraud is the use of stolen information such as making fake ID's and fake bank accounts"),
Flashcard(question: " Invoice Scams", answer: "using fraudulent invoices to steal from a company"),
Flashcard(question: " Credential Harvesting", answer: "the use of MITM attacks, DNS poisoning, phishing, etc. to amass large numbers of credentials (username / password combinations) for reuse."),
Flashcard(question: " Reconnaissance", answer: "- Information gathering about a target network"),
Flashcard(question: " Hoax", answer: "Cyber hoax scams are attacks that exploit unsuspecting users to provide valuable information, such as login credentials or money."),
Flashcard(question: " Impersonation", answer: "typically involves an email that seems to come from a trusted source."),
Flashcard(question: " Watering hole attack", answer: "security exploit in which the attacker seeks to compromise a specific group of end users by infecting websites that members of the group are known to visit. The goal is to infect a targeted user's computer and gain access to the network at the target's place of employment."),
Flashcard(question: " Typo squatting", answer: "type of cybersquatting used by imposters that involve registering domains with intentionally misspelled names of popular web addresses to install malware on the user's system"),
Flashcard(question: " Pretexting", answer: "the practice of presenting oneself as someone else in order to obtain private information."),
Flashcard(question: " Authority: an attacker may try to appear to have a certain level authority.", answer: "Intimidation: may try to make the victim think that something terrible is going to happen if they don't comply with the attacker's wishes."),
Flashcard(question: " Consensus: An attacker may try to sway the mind of a victim using names they are familiar with, saying that such ones provided them information (they are fishing for) in the past and you should be able to do the same.", answer: "Scarcity: An attacker may try to set a time limit on a victim so that they can comply with their wishes by a certain deadline."),
Flashcard(question: " Familiarity: they make you familiar with them on the phone and make you want to do things for them.", answer: "Trust: The attacker in this case can claim to be a friend or close associate of someone you may know very well and that's trusted."),
Flashcard(question: " Bluejacking", answer: "Some users with Bluetooth-enabled mobiles use this technology to send anonymous text messages to strangers."),
Flashcard(question: " a sophisticated, possibly long-running computer hack that is perpetrated by large, well-funded organizations such as governments", answer: "Advanced Persistent Threat (APT)"),
Flashcard(question: " Current or former employee, contractor or other partner that has or had authorized access and intentionally misused that access", answer: "Insider threats"),
Flashcard(question: " Hacktivists", answer: "A protester seeking to make a political point by leveraging technology tools, often through system infiltration, defacement, or damage."),
Flashcard(question: " Script kiddies", answer: "Individuals who want to break into computers to create damage, yet lack the advanced knowledge of computers and networks needed to do so."),
Flashcard(question: " Resources/funding (attributes of actors)", answer: "APTs, and nation states have a penchant for long-term attacks, which requires this which only major organizations or government can manage over time."),
Flashcard(question: " Intent/motivation (attributes of actors)", answer: "This can be simple or multifold in nature. A script kiddie is just trying to make a technique work. A more skilled threat actor is usually pursuing a specific objective, such as trying to make a point as a hacktivist. At the top of the intent pyramid is the APT threat actor, whose intent or motivation is at least threefold."),
 ]);
}